<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
	<string id="item_cheburashka_name">
		<text>Cheburashka</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_cheburashka_desc">
		<text>Old toy of soviet cartoon character, looks like it was in anomaly for a while. It's warm and smells fur. Toy's darned on its back.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_guitar_sidr_name">
		<text>Sidor's guitar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_guitar_sidr_desc">
		<text>Sidor's guitar.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_yashik_weapon_name">
		<text>Box with weapon</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_yashik_weapon_desc">
		<text>Heavy box with assault rifles. Has a code lock.</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="af-night-star_teterev">
		<text>"Black Star"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_zone_artifact_af-night-star_teterev">
		<text>"Black Star" is a rare type of "Night Star" artifact. Origin is unknown, artifact gains fire resistance of its host, unlike "Night Star".</text>
	</string>
	
	
	<string id="item_bp_mily_otschet_name">
		<text>New path report</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_bp_mily_otschet_desc">
		<text>Military report about recovering old blocked path between Agroprom and Escape. According data path was stable before Second Big Surge in times of faction war. After Second Big Surge Zone's anomal energy sealed the path. Now there's possibility to reviving old path.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_af_esc_anomaly_name">
		<text>Unknown artifact</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_esc_anomaly_desc">
		<text>Strange unknown artifact. Highly radioactive with no other remarkable properties.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_antena_name">
		<text>Microphone</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_antena_desc">
		<text>Directional microphone with high sensitivity. Clearly distinguishes even between low sounds at a distance of over 200 meters.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_pda_friend_barman_name">
		<text>Schvid's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_friend_barman_desc">
		<text>Schvid's PDA. Working. Copied undamaged records:\nRecord ¹1:\nYesterday saw three bandits captured one Duty soldier. What an assholes!\nRecord ¹2:\nBandits apparently pluck! They have, according to our data, several Duty prisoners.\nRecord ¹3:\nToday was a lucky day - I found three "Mincer Meat" artifacts.\nRecord ¹4:\nWe've struggled with Freedom soldiers, but we managed to fight back.\nRecord ¹5:\nOur group was captured by Freedom, they took away our weapons. They want to take us to a small tower next to the vagon and force us to get the artifacts from it. They don't want to climb by themselves - there is strong radiation. We trie...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_af_for_night_stalker_name">
		<text>"Black Soul"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_for_night_stalker_desc">
		<text>"Black Soul" artifact. It has a very negative properties when touched, can cause dizziness and nausea. Exhibits strong local gravitational field - it is difficult to tear hands from the artifact. Prolonged contact with him would have serious implications for the organism.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_af_of_doch_starik_name">
		<text>Doll</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_of_doch_starik_desc">
		<text>Oldman daughter's doll. It looks quite unusual and have a strange effect on the owner, causing a slight dizziness and noise hallucinations.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kid_zapisi_name">
		<text>Notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kid_zapisi_desc">
		<text>Regular school notebook. Gnarled children's handwriting with errors and "sunshines" on the sidelines. Notepad almost all rotted, you can read only last few pages.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_wpn_of_qest_on_elevator_name">
		<text>Sniper rifle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_wpn_of_qest_on_elevator_desc">
		<text>Sniper rifle, receiver is torn up by cartridge explosion. There is a strange symbol carved on the butt.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_kolba_dummy_name">
		<text>Empty flask</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_dummy_desc">
		<text>Empty lab flask.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_name">
		<text>Flask with water</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_desc">
		<text>Lab flask filled with water from swamp.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_zombie_name">
		<text>Serum</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_kolba_zombie_desc">
		<text>Serum. The ugly sight and smell of it is in harmony with the medicine appointment. It causes a temporary condition, close to zombieness.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_treasure_of_figa_name">
		<text>Note from Figa's stash.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_treasure_of_figa_desc">
		<text>Note from Figa's stash. Content:\n"I have long been studying anomalous phenomena in the yantar territory. Most recently I observed a strange glow at the plant near compressor building reminiscent of glimpses of the artifact, but much stronger. It occurs only at certain hours. It was about ten o'clock at night, I was close, but I was afraid to go further. Besides, I had a headache - apparently bipsizon effect was running out ... I had to leave. Recently Sakharov run out of this miracle drug (very inappropriate!), but I will try to get there again anyway. If I'll hesitate, glow may be noticed by someone else! In case of I'll become zombied, I'm leaving the fish here - Sakharov promised to cure me. I hope everything will be OK and I won't need this message.\nFiga\n\nP.S. If you are reading this note, I'm most likely dead. In that case, I have left most important documents related to the laboratory at Yantar lake that I found earlier in the bus at the road leading to the factory gate. Be careful, there's very serious stuff going on... I think I detected something about origin of the Zone.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dnevnik_tomsona_name">
		<text>Professor Thompson's diary</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_dnevnik_tomsona_desc">
		<text>Professor Thompson's diary.\n
		2006, March 21.\nI, Joseph Carl Thompson is deputy of professor Mengelin - our science head. We're busy of quite dangerous experiments and in case of emergency I have started this diary. A week ago we received a group of criminals convicted to death. Looks like government decided that these guys are most appropriate "test subjects". That's a switch! We've had enough problems without all this criminal staff. On the other hand, their intellect is low so we can observe cahnges more clearly. We've spend a lot of time on project which, according our theories, would boost human intellectual abilities a lot. We haven't tested it yet because of lack of proper test subjects but now with full barn of it we're expecting first real results.\n\n
		2006, March 23.\nToday we were conducted first major experiment with working equipment. First it was smooth, devices showed stable boost of cortex performance and throughput of subcortex synapces. But then performance started to change unpredictably and one of subjects began to shout loudly. Interesting, he said "Zone", "April 12th", "Consciousness" among other unarticulate shouts. Then he fall in psychosis and convulsions... we had to break experiment and give him sedatives. Nonetheless, subject began to demand of killing him and other subjects after he woke up. Wild shouts disturbed other subjects, so we transfered that particular one to X-18 lab to second science team which is conducting experiments on human body to gain its abilities. They don't need intellectual subjects so it will good for them.\n\n
		2006, March 26.\nLooks like our experiments are going to end. We've got first amazing results! Phenomenal data, enormous brain activity. Patients started to think way more faster and their abstract thinking was developed large (subjects were just a criminals).  Their IQ reached 200! But there wer bad news also - situation turned dangerous. It was looked like all subjects began to show hypnosis ability. Personnel started to fear subjects and we've had to equip assistants with weapons and to develop new instructions about working in pairs.\n\n
		2006, March 27.\nStrange things are happened in lab: professor Mengelin, our head, is like out of his mind today! Looks like he is obsessed with some genial idea or he's falling in psychosis... Without any reason he ordered to eliminate all of our subjects. And when our experiments started to give results! My collegues said that he spent whole night with one if the lab units when he didn't let anyone in. Look like he discovered something, I'm not sure, what, but his order can't be questioned by us. Security team took subjects out of lab but didn't return back. Security chief is nervous, constantly calling somewhere.\n\n
		2006, March 28.\nSecurity returned. They looks slightly inhibited, don't remember some things. But they're all claiming that order was done and bodies were buried. They were not capable to explain where they were last day and why some of them lost their weapons... All group was transfered to medical unit. Mengelin spent all day to explain his new idea - new project developed from old one, aimed to discover an ability to unite human consciousnesses for solution of one problem. "O-Consciousness" project, he developed it, when he locked himself in lab. Impressive project, but looks quite unrealizable for me. In case of success we're expecting a giant leap of humanity, not just some breakthorugh! We're working passionly, updating equipment for new purposes. All of us are excited and enthusiastic.\n\n
		2006, April 2.\nThere're strange things happening - we were able to create some object that can give endless knoledge to human when contacted. I think, he's crazy, as a side effect of lab unit fields. But that strange object is definitely can change consciousness when close to him. Also object can be touched only in certain time. I have no ideas so far why it's possible.\n\n
		2006, April 3.\n\nTonight Mengelin shot himself in his office. There's a mess in lab, government agents were arrived and took all of documents. They're disassembling our equipment and drove it away without any explanation. Also group of well armed militants was arrived with them. Strange camo and black hats. I can't recognize their signs. They're acting quietly, looking unkindly, and our security team was disappeared. All proceedings were stopped, we were not able to test strange object. Looks like we won't be able to do this - government obviously decided to stop our experiments. I was appointed as a head of science team and got an order to destroy all evidences. But that object is priceless! It's a single specimen of our experiments! I can't destroy it. When we shipped equipment, I sneaked to the plant and hid the object. Later I'm going to return and collect the object... Hope, I'll make it...\n\n
		P.S. In case if I'll forget the place - I hid it under the pipes near compressor building that is located near main project building in the yard of the plant.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_unknow_zapisi_tomsona_name">
		<text>Big pile of papers</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_unknow_zapisi_tomsona_desc">
		<text>Big pile of scitnce papers. You can't understand it, papers partially encrypted and filled with science terminology. Looks like these are only for scientists.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_serdce_yantar_desc">
		<text>O-21 object. You feel strange extension of consciousness with undescribable clarity when near it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_af_serdce_yantar_name">
		<text>O-21 object</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_case_use_rub_name">
		<text>Case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_case_use_rub_desc">
		<text>Case with unknown content. Locked with code lock.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_a_case_name">
		<text>Note</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_a_case_desc">
		<text>If you're who I'm thinking that you know, where Strelok stash is. In that stash you'll find a key - a code for case. And if i'm mistaking in you that you're not going there for your safety. If I'm not - be aware: switch in X-10 lab is mined and connected to tanks with nerve gas. When disabled by stranger all lab will blow out and nerve gas will begin to fill all the rooms. Instructions for disabling switch are located in case which is protected also: there's a tank with compressed "witch's jelly" which will be released in case of opening attempt. All the data (and thief) will be destroyed in that case, So if you're stranger - leave the case and walk your way.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_2_a_case_desc">
		<text>If you're reading this, I was right about you: you're who I was thinking. But I has some doubts about you and hope they are excess.\nThere is only one part of code in case. Messanger has other part. Meet him near old village near Freedom base.\nLooks like Monolith claimed a war to you, heh, like in old times. I can't help you so faras I have so many enemys now. You don't need excessive attention. Hope, you'll recognize me when you'll meet me.\n Case password: 20061204</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_zapis_3_a_case_desc">
		<text>"rksr" is missing part of code. Yes, you'll need to enter the passcode and then pull the switch. Hope, you'll find, what you seek. Good luck!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_monolit_name">
		<text>PDA of monolith soldier</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_monolit_desc">
		<text>PDA of monolith soldier. Only one record: "Brothers, one of infideles got an ability to reach of sanctuary of Holy Monolith. At any cost you should stop him! It's known that he's carrying a nickname Marked One, doing bussiness with Barman and professor Sakharov. Photo is attached. There're facts that he has some companions. All of them should be destroyed, but he is a main target. Protective helmet, that is owned by him, should be gathered and delivered to old ones. Helmet should be destroyed if it's unable to gather."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pol_code_of_case_name">
		<text>Part of the code to case</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pol_code_of_case_desc">
		<text>First part of the code to case: "cnfkrth"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_pda_scoryi_name">
		<text>Quick's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_scoryi_desc">
		<text>Quick's PDA.\nFirst record:\n"I'm with Sitnik returning from raid. We have plenty of loot. But he's strange, I don't like him. I noticed changed knots on bag on last rest - some stranger messed with them. Sitnik is only who could. Ad he kept watch last. I think, he can betray me. This is my last voyage in Zone. I have enough money to cure Mila now. I've wade through it for a long time! And now, when my goal is close, I can taste a happy life for our family! I miss you, my dear!\nWe're heading to Sidor, we're close. I want to reach Escape ASAP and say bye to Sitnik! He's no good. I can't understand, why he bothers me so much... But he's dangerous... That's it, I'm ending this and we'll go..."\nArchive record, high priority: Wife address (personal account): u18no00qbv5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_notebook_mercs_name">
		<text>Mercenary's notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_notebook_mercs_desc">
		<text>Mercenary's notebook</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_box_moneys_name">
		<text>Bag with money</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_box_moneys_desc">
		<text>Bag with money.</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="item_pda_preobr_name">
		<text>Preobrajensky's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_preobr_desc">
		<text>Professor Preobrajensky's PDA. Records:\n
		"First day. Time: 21-04.\nVolunteers appeared today, they agreed to guide me to research place. We've got there smoothly - guides were experienced. We established lager fast and professional. I even managed to make some readings.\n
		Second day. Time: 19-25.\n There was raining all day. We couldn't establish fire so we ate cold meat at breakfast. My devices can't work while raining. I just wandered around, collected some plants just to save my day. Hope, there won't be raining tomorrow.\n
		Third day. Time: 21-20.\n Good day, wonderful. Didn't eat breakfast, just went to take readings. When I was in field, my guiders met two men. All four talked and looke on me. I was working at that time. After 20 minutes strange stalkers gone. I asked about them during dear but Toha just strangely looked at me and winked. I don't like it.\nFourth day. Time: 11-00.\nThose two stalkers returned about a half of an hour ago. I was under the tent and stalkers talked near the bonfire. I heard some words and got that they ventured something. Especially I was frightened of "... there're no problems with him..." and "... customer is waiting...". This is no good..."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_stebel_ri_name">
		<text>Stem of plant</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_stebel_ri_desc">
		<text>Stem of plant Ranunculus insolita.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_lekar_for_sidor_name">
		<text>Cure</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_lekar_for_sidor_desc">
		<text>Cure made from plant Ranunculus insolita.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_gribnik_name">
		<text>Mushroomer's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_gribnik_desc">
		<text>PDA of stalker named Mushroomers.\nLast record:\n"There's strong virus in tank that we've found. It's that we've wanted. I believe there're people interested in it in the Zone."</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_leshyi_name">
		<text>Goblin's PDA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="item_pda_leshyi_desc">
		<text>PDA of stalker named Goblin.\nLast record:\n"Mushroomer was killed. Now, when we found such a valuable thing, I don't need him. I'v got a customers for virus. One dose already was sold to Adder, he's bandit, I guess. He talked about Sidor. Want to poison him? Good. Old man owned good place too much."</text>
	</string>
</string_table>