<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Hello, Stalker! I hope you came here to help us?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Got it, I'll stay on guard. Thank you, Zaharich.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1_1_1">
		<text>Oh, really... I think I know where they moved the camp, son. But if I am right - it's bad, really bad. In the entire Ravine there is only one such place - hidden and protected from all sides. On the road from the Dark Valley there is a tunnel in the narrow part of the canyon. In that tunnel, if memory serves me well, there was a shed where the road workers kept their tools for tunnel maintenance. It seems to me, that's where they headed. But if that's true, you probably won't find them alive. A controller took a liking to that shed, evil and tough. He lures people there and eats them, but sometimes he leaves for a few days. If they went there, he got them for sure, which is sure going to make him happy, that accursed evil creature. If you go there, equip well, and be careful. If the controller is there - you are in trouble, and will have to fight. Also - the tunel is full of anomalies, so don't believe everything you see. </text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1_1">
		<text>I don't know it myself, was just going to ask if you saw it. They said it was a comfortable place, protected from all sides and hidden.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1_1">
		<text>Moved where?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1_1">
		<text>We had no contact with them for a while, I was sent to find out if anything had happened to them. I heard they moved the camp, and we haven't heard from them since.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_1">
		<text>Which scientists? Those that were taking measurements here from the very beginning? I saw them, I used to bring them fresh food from time to time, when they had trouble getting their food supplies. It's been a while however, but why do you ask?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_lab_dialog_0">
		<text>Listen, Zaharich, have you seen a scientists' camp here in the Ravine?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>I heard your conversation. What's going on here?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_2_1">
		<text>I was just passing by.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>We were attacked by bandits from Kulgavy's band. They wanted to kick us out from the Sawmill, and they would have done it easily by now, because they are much better armed than we are, and all we have is hunting rifles. However, we managed to capture one of their scouts, and the bandits are hesitant to attack. He must know something they need.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Interesting. Why don't you just release the captive and leave?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>If we run now, we will run again and again. We must wipe this scum out!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>I don't even know how to help you. Let me scout out how many we are dealing with here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>I see you never dealt with criminals. Their word can't be trusted at all - we give them back the prisoner and they will just shoot us all. Whatever we do, we must be sure we'll make it out alive.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>What does this scout know? Have you tried getting it out of him?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>We tried, but he's keeping his mouth shut. Bachinsky even punched him a couple of times, but that didn't help. We didn't really try too hard after that. And why do we even want to know the bandits' business? We are just trying to save our own hide here.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>That information might actually help. Maybe I can make him talk?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>OK, you can try, but if you start torturing him and he screams, the bandits might hear and start the attack.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>I'll keep that in mind.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Did you see the kind of weapons my guys have? The bandits, by the way, have sub-machine guns and grenades, and also more men. I don't want to lose my guys. They are all that is left from the Scout group after the expedition failed. But if you are sure you want to help us...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>%c[255,255,118,118]I'm sure. I want to see those guys six feet under!%c[default]</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>You are right, we have to think this through.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>Consider the situation yourself. Listen... Maybe you can make a deal with them? Or at least distract them, while we make a run for it? That would be nice. I'm begging you - go to their camp, take a look, talk to their boss, and then report back to me, OK?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_start_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>OK, I'll go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenn_pomilov_dialog1_phrase_1">
		<text>Flea wouldn't budge, but he agreed to tell us where he hid the information if we let him go. What do you say?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenn_pomilov_dialog1_phrase_2">
		<text>I say it's worth it. I suspect that if we get that info, we'll be able to get rid of the bandits for good. Tell Flea to tell us where he hid it, and we let him go if we can resolve this conflict to our satisfaction.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="yuriy_plenn_pomilov_dialog1_phrase_3">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_0">
		<text>Looks like you are in deep shit, brother?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Why are you concerned? How would you like to be the first to take a hike?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Today is not a good day to piss me off.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>What do you want?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>I need the info you were carrying to your boss. How much do you want for it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>More than you can get, lame.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Name the price, and I will decide myself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Are you that stupid? I am a captive here, what am I going to do with it?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>I can arrange a deal to let you go.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>Make the deal, and I will tell you. The main thing for me right now is to save myself. I have a feeling there is going to be quite a brawl, and I might be the first to bite the dust. If you ensure my safety, I will let you know where I hid the info.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ds_plenniy_start_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>OK, I'll talk to Yuri.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Yuri promised to let you go if you tell us where you left the information.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>All right, the hell with it! Somewhere here, not far from the Sawmill, I dropped my backpack with a note. It was dark at night, and then they hit me over the head when they grabbed me, so I don't remember exactly, but you should be able to find it with no problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="plenniy_shron_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>If I don't, you are going to be the one with a problem.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Greetings, living soul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Hello to you too, grandpa. How is life?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Life, or rather what's left of it... Little by little, day after day... as many as god wills it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>How did you happen to get in the Zone?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>I didn't get here, the Zone grew around me. I used to live not far from here, in the village to the North. During the evacuation I decided to stay. And so I live here on whatever nature provides. The radiation here is not too bad.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Why didn't you stay in the village? Why do you live in this hut?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>Bandits kicked me out about a year ago, heathens.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_hello_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>sorry about that.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>Hey, grandpa, did anyone come to see you  lately, besides me?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>There was a young lad, very talkative... Laughing and telling jokes all the time, even though he looked pretty raggedy himself.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>Raggedy?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Someone was after him, so he came here to hide out. I realized it right away, even though he didn't tell me anything. I've seen it before.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>But why did he come to you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>Very few people know about my hut: only the Scouts at the Sawmill, and now you. It's pretty deep in the woods, a good place to hide when someone is after you. He didn't look like a murderer or a thief, I can see right through people. He had kind eyes, and that's why I let him in.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>And where is he now? Left?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_8">
		<text>You see... It's a sad story. Greed got the best of him. So many it killed! Only the bullets and the beasts killed more. He stayed here for three days only. In the evening I used to tell him some stories I had heard from locals. Once I told him about the Death-zone and the "Light" artifact...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_9">
		<text>What is this "Death-zone"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_10">
		<text>That's a place nearby, a real death trap. The Evil forced the earth to pump up and rise up in the air, and holds it like that. The Evil is so strong there, that it kills all life that touches it. Nothing can pass by it, everyone drops dead - animals, people, even birds. And you can't trick it: neither with a scientific suit, nor with a gadget. It's also treacherous - it lures the unsuspecting with pretty things. Rumour has it that at the center of the place lies an artifact called "Darkness". Whoever finds it, will discover many of the Zone's treasures and the hidden places that one can't see with a naked eye. That's the legend...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_11">
		<text>So the Talkative went to look for that artifact?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_12">
		<text>Yes. I tried to talk him out of it, but he didn't heed the old man, and left for his death. He never came back, may god take mercy on his soul.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_13">
		<text>Tell me, grandpa, where is this "Death-zone"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_14">
		<text>Do you want to die from the Evil Force too? Come to your sense, save your soul!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_15">
		<text>No, I'm just curious.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_16">
		<text>In the woods, to the West of here. Stay away from that place!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_17">
		<text>Listen, Zaharich... I need to get in there.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_18">
		<text>Greed got you too.. Oh!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_19">
		<text>It's not greed. I need some information, and a part of it was with the lad that got lost in the "Death-zone". Maybe I should ask the scientists?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_20">
		<text>What kind of information could be so important? However... There is a way. It is very risky, almost as dangerous as the Evil of that anomaly.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_21">
		<text>We'll pick the lesser of the two evils.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_22">
		<text>Legend has it, that the death radiation of that zone is many times amplified radiation of one extremely harmful artifact. The artifact was formed near an old soviet power transformer, and it somehow amplified its harmful effect and spread it over a large area, creating the "Death-zone".</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_23">
		<text>Supposably.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_24">
		<text>The point is, that this artifact called "Darkness" was at one time a part of one whole artifact, that was destroyed by one overly curious stalker. The second half is called "Light" and has an opposite, healing effect. Together the two halves balance each other out. So, if someone has the "Light", he can enter the "Death-zone" unharmed.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_25">
		<text>Where do I find this "Light"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_26">
		<text>Therein lies the problem. The stalker that split the artifact in half, perished a long time ago, and took the secret of its whereabouts to the grave with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_27">
		<text>Dead end?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_28">
		<text>I don't think so... I will tell you a secret. I know a stalker, rather not even a stalker... So he knew that curious guy, and knows where his grave is.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_29">
		<text>Tell me his name.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_30">
		<text>Hold on, don't be in such a rush! Oh, youth...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_31">
		<text>What is it, grandpa? Did you forget his name?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_32">
		<text>A name like that you don't forget.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_33">
		<text>Then what is it? Maybe you can tell me in exchange for something?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_34">
		<text>I will tell you for free, but believe me - it is better for you not to know it at all. And I am not in a habit to even utter his name, just in case...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_35">
		<text>Who is it then?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_36">
		<text>Let's do this: I will give you a book, you'll read it and find out. The main character of the book is the one you need. It's all because I don't want to utter his name, not to summon evil. Here, take it, read it, and then I will tell you where you can find this... man.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_boltun_dialog_phrase_37">
		<text>You've indeed fogged this issue to a real mystery, grandpa! OK, give me the book.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I've read the book.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>Do you understand who I was talking about?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>But the Dark Salker is a myth.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>Well, if you think so, go up the hill southwest of here. This "myth" often appears there, and not alone. And one more thing! Do not shoot the dog, understand? Or you will regret it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>Every day I get more and more convinced that the Zone is a land of miracles. OK, will he lead me to the grave of the stalker that used to posess the "Light"?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>I think so. Just be very careful with him.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="hunter_about_darkstalk_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>OK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_1">
		<text>I was wondering around and found something interesting...</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_2">
		<text>What kind of nonsense is this?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_3">
		<text>I found a note that you were going to switch allegiance to another boss, and then set Kulgavy up so he wouldn't wring your neck.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_4">
		<text>You bitch! Give me the note or die!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_5">
		<text>If you kill me, the note will be delivered, and that's not going to be good for your health. So I suggest you get the hell out of here!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_6">
		<text>OK, frayer, we'll meet again someday in a dark corner!</text>
	</string>
	<string id="prof_surrend_dialog_phrase_7">
		<text>If we both live long enough!</text>
	</string>
</string_table>

