	<string id="cit_doctor_meet_conclusion">
		<text>Meeting with the Doctor</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_meet_conclusion_text">
		<text>I don't know what to say..Should I be happy or sad? I found out that I am the Shooter. A Shooter who lost his memory in one of the last passages leading to the center of the Zone. A Shooter who lost all of his friends except for the Doctor. A Shooter who found out something that made him be followed. What did I find out? Next question. The Doctor managed to save the key and the location of the secret stash of our group at Pripyat. It's located in one of the rooms of the old hotel in the center. He says that there must be something there that will shed some light on the "Granter of Wishes" or Monolith. He knows only one thing: after the second to last scouting expedition to the Cherbobyl NPP I kept on saying that there's something shady with Monolith. Well Monolith, we're going to try and deal with you. Who are you and what are you?</text>
	</string>
	<string id="cit_doctor_task_0_art">
		<text>Doctor: When we last met, you left me the key from the secret stash at Pripyat and the diagram which showed how to find it...I managed to save them...the Mercs didn't find them...Here...Maybe you'll find something else there....And also you kept on mumbling that there was something shady with Monolith...That's for sure...</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_1">
		<text>Data segment 1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_1_text">
		<text>"Â Âast seaÿ one cÿn see purple katatsumoridako with many of long thin hands, stick out of round shell thirty foot in size with shaÿp peaks, its eyes are rotten and it's covered with polypus. hen it floats it lies in water like an island, spreadÿÿg smell and defeÿÿte with white to lure fish and birds. hen they arriÿe, it grabs them with hands and feÿd itself./DATA CORRUPTED/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_2">
		<text>Data segment 2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_2_text">
		<text>/DATA CORRUPTED/Â uring moonlight night it lies and wÿllow, looking in the skyes and thinÿing about abyss where it was erupted from. That -houghÿs so horrible that people aÿe terriÿied and becoÿe like tigers." Qhis is a excerpt from ancient ÿapanese legend that can describÿ our situation in >vankov-32 exactly. Ecological disasteÿ zone is here, stalkers often call this place like Ãity-32 or Ìead Ãity./DISK READ ERROR/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_3">
		<text>Data segment 3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_3_text">
		<text>/CONTROL CHECKSUM IS WRONG/Fhis name is selfdescribing - city flooded with zombied stalkers, which barely can count as a living being. Ís far as we know, this situatiÿn in city exists since first Âlowout. Local Ìerritory attÿacts zombied from all Çone for some reasons while city itself covered with emission field with high intensity, even higher than on Yantar./DATA CORRUPTED/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_4">
		<text>Data segment 4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_4_text">
		<text>/DISK READ ERROR/Â t deterÿines two goaÿs of our expedition provided by ÎÎÍ mandatory of special zone of ecological disasteÿ. sirsÿ goal is to investigate this unique region and seconÿ goal is to find emissiÿn source which origin is stiÿl unknown because of absence of science labs in this region according our data./CONTROL CHECKSUM IS WRONG/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_5">
		<text>Data segment 5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_5_text">
		<text>/DATA CORRUPTED/sding intelligence we susÿect that there is anoth¸r aimanov emitteÿ somewhere here. -ccording docs founded in Íjoprom InstiÈÈte there were two prototypes of emitters, but performance of second one was too far from basic parameters. There were sÿme inciÿents, it was considered harmful and was deactivated soon./DISK READ ERROR/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_6">
		<text>Data segment 6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_6_text">
		<text>/CONTROL CHECKSUM IS WRONG/Its Ìtorage sÿte remained unknown and military stalker expeditiÿns were unable to find possible location of emitteÿ prototype. So Ït's a possibilÿty that emission field over Èvankov-32 is generatÿng by this second prototype. TÂere are some evidenÿes of this version: unusual emission fiÿld parameters and presence of psycÿic suppression fÿeld./DATA CORRUPTED/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_7">
		<text>Data segment 7</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_7_text">
		<text>/DISK READ ERROR/Îowever it's unclÿar how emittÿr can wÿrk without propÿr infrastrÿcture. In particular, emitter requirÿs continious supply of feed mix, containing glucÿse, and water coÿling. Âll mechanisms also requirÿs electricity, so this version is a subject ÿf sÿriÿus dÿubts./DATA CORRUPTED/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_8">
		<text>Data segment 8</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_8_text">
		<text>/DATA CORRUPTED/Îo plan of work in Èvankov-32 consiÿt of: measuring of main parametÿrs of emission and its impact to living organisms, triangulÿtion of emission source, its recovery and investigation of neutralization possibilities. Äoÿ protection of personnel expeditÿon will be equipped with experimental protection equipment, ÿvaluation of which is also one of our gÿals./DISK READ ERROR/</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_9">
		<text>Data segment 9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="deadcity_science_report_p_9_text">
		<text>/CONTROL CHECKSUM IS WRONG/Ïersonnel should carry out work with caution, ÿaving science datÿ has first degree priority in case of emergency. Âersonnel evÿcuÿtion is secondÿry. Òext is equipmeÿt evacuation. Ñersonnel safety is main duty for expÿdition guard so data safÿty is our mane duty, collegues./DATA CORRUPTED/</text>
	</string>	