<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- 	#include "text\rus\include_stable_new_items.xml" -->
<!-- 	#include "text\rus\include_stable_magazines.xml" -->

<!-- This section is for ammunition -->
<!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x39-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 7.62x39 mm rounds.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39-dummy">
		<text>7.62x39 cartridge pack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39-dummy_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39fmj">
		<text>7.62x39 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39fmj_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm FMJ</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x39fmj">
		<text>The 7.62x39 mm intermediate rifle cartridge was designed by N.M. Elizarov and B.V. Semin in 1943. The cartridge is known coloquially as the M43, and sometimes called ".30 Short Russian" in the US. 7.62 FMJ (57-N-231) denotes a bullet with a heat-treated steel core. The round can punch through a steel helmet at up to 900 meters and pierce standard body armor at up to 600 meters. At 100 meters, the round can destroy 12-15 cm-thick brick wall. The bullet has no distinctive color.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39ap">
		<text>7.62x39 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39ap_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm AP</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x39ap">
		<text>The 7.62x39 mm intermediate round with an armor-piercing bullet (7N23). Developed in the late 1990s by D.I. Veronskiy and V.V. Zakharyaschev, and adopted by the Russian military in 2002. This new round has over three times the penetrative power of the FMJ round, while retaining the FMJ round's trajectory. It can penetrate a Russian 6B5 vest at up to 250 meters. At 100 meters, the round can destroy 12-15 cm-thick brick wall. The bullet has a black tip for identification.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->	
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39apf">
		<text>7.62x39 mm API rounds</text>
	</string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39apf_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm API</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x39apf">
		<text>The 7.62x39 mm intermediate round with an armor-piercing incendiary bullet (57-BZ-231) is designed to defeat lightly-armored targets at distances up to 300 meters. The bullet ignites after penetration of body armor or thick walls. It can punch through a steel helmet at up to 1100 meters and pierce standard body armor at up to 1000 meters. The round can also pierce 7mm-thick hardened steel at up to 200 meters. The bullet has a black tip with a red belt.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
<string id="ammo-7.62x39b">
		<text>7.62x39 mm subsonic rounds</text>
	</string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39b_s">
		<text>7.62x39 mm subsonic</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x39b">
		<text>The 7.62x39 mm M43 subsonic cartridge "US" (57-N-231U). The bullet features a weighted steel core, and is designed to be fired with a silencer/flash suppressor. Can penetrate a steel helmet at up to 400 meters and penetrate standard body armor at up to 75 meters. The bullet has a black tip with a green belt.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-5.45x39-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 5.45x39 mm rounds.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="ammo-5.45x39-dummy">
		<text>5.45x39 mm cartridge pack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-dummy_s">
		<text>5.45x39 mm</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39fmj">
		<text>5.45x39 mm EPR rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39fmj_s">
		<text>5.45x39 mm EPR</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-5.45x39fmj">
		<text>5.45x39 mm low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge. The small-caliber bullet provides a flatter trajectory, increasing its effective range. The round's disadvantages include lower blunt stopping power (although the bullet has a great tendency to yaw), and its tendency to ricochet. 5.45x39 mm EPR (7N10) denotes enhanced penetration, with a heat-treated steel core. Standard in the Russian and Ukrainian armies since 1992, replacing the 7N6 and 7N6M. The bullet is lacquer-coated and has no distinctive color.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39ap">
		<text>5.45x39 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39ap_s">
		<text>5.45x39 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-5.45x39ap">
		<text>5.45x39 mm low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge with an armor-piercing bullet (7N22), designed to penetrate advanced body armor and light vehicles. The bullet can penetrate a 6mm-thick armor plate (standard for modern body armor) at up to 250 meters with 80% reliability. The bullet is lacquer-coated and has a black tip.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-5.56x45-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 5.56x45 mm rounds.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="ammo-5.56x45-dummy">
		<text>5.56x45 mm cartridge pack</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-dummy_s">
		<text>5.56x45 mm</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45ss190">
		<text>5.56x45 mm FMJ rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45ss190_s">
		<text>5.56x45 mm FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-5.56x45ss190">
		<text>5.56x45 mm/.223 Rem low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge with a full-metal jacket (FMJ). Based on the .223 Remington hunting cartridge, the SS109 bullet, designed by Fabrique Nationale in Belgium, was adopted by NATO in the mid-1980s under index STANAG 4172.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 mm AP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-5.56x45ap">
		<text>5.56x45 mm NATO low-recoil intermediate rifle cartridge with a armour piercing bullet, was designed to penetrate advanced body armor and light vehicles.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x54-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 7,62õ54 mm cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-dummy">
		<text>Pack of 7,62õ54</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-dummy_s">
		<text>7,62õ54 mm</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54_7h1">
		<text>7,62õ54 7N1 cartridges</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54_7h1_s">
		<text>7,62õ54 mm 7N1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x54_7h1">
		<text>7,62õ54 mm R untary rifle cartridge (Rimmed, with jutted bead) was developed in 1891 as a munition for Mosin rifle. After modernization in 1930 cartrudge was received M1908/30 designation. When SVD was developed cartridge was modernized to improve accuracy and power and was received 7N1 designation. Cartridge has bullet with full-metal jacket. No specific color for bullet.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54ap">
		<text>7,62õ54 7N26 cartridges</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54ap_s">
		<text>7,62õ54 mm 7N26</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x54ap">
		<text>7,62õ54 mm 7N26 AP armor-piercing rifle cartridge. In 1990 there was a modernization program for 7.62x54R cartridges. In 1998 standard 7N13 cartridge was improved with cone metal core and in 1999 new 7N26 cartridge was stated as standard armour-piercing munition. 7N26 armor-piercing cartridges has no specific label, cartridge pack is labeled with black line.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7,62õ54 7N14 cartridges</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
		<text>7,62õ54 mm 7N14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7,62õ54 mm 7N14 AP armor-piercing sniper rifle cartridge. In 1990 there was a modernization program for 7.62x54R cartridges. One of the goals was to improve piercing ability for bullet. 7N14 sniper rifle cartridge has improved piercing ability and accuracy.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // --><!-- // --><!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-7.62x25-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 7,62õ25 mm cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-dummy">
		<text>Pack of 7,62õ25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-dummy_s">
		<text>7,62õ25 mm</text>
	</string>
<!-- // --><!-- // --><!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-9x18-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 9õ18 mm cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-dummy">
		<text>Pack of 9õ18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-dummy_s">
		<text>9õ18 mm</text>
	</string>
<!-- // --><!-- // --><!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-9x19-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 9õ19 mm cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-dummy">
		<text>Pack of 9õ19</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-dummy_s">
		<text>9õ19 mm</text>
	</string>
<!-- // --><!-- // --><!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-11.43x23-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of .45 ACP cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-dummy">
		<text>Pack of .45 ACP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-dummy_s">
		<text>.45 ACP</text>
	</string>
<!-- // --><!-- // --><!-- // -->
	<string id="enc_weapons_ammo-12x70-dummy">
		<text>Empty pack of 12 caliber cartridges.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-dummy">
		<text>Pack of 12 caliber</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-dummy_s">
		<text>12 calib.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog25">
		<text>VOG-25 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog25_s">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog25">
		<text>40-mm caliber VOG-25 fragmentation rounds (7P17). The grenade is standalone and is caseless (propellant with primer is located on the rear of the grenade). During firing, the propellant powder gases continue to burn after the grenade leaves the launcher barrel, serving as an afterburner to increase trajectory while also lowering recoil slightly.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-vog25p">
		<text>VOG-25PM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog25p_s">
		<text>VOG-25PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog25p">
		<text>40-mm caliber VOG-25 fragmentation rounds ("Jump" modernized, 7P45). The main difference from the VOG-25 is the use of the VGM-P fuse, which has a bounding charge, allowing the grenade to explode in mid-air, or after crushing through cover. Provides a 50% increase in lethality.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-vog25tb">
		<text>VG-40TB rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog25tb_s">
		<text>VG-40TB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog25tb">
		<text>40-mm caliber VG-40TB thermobaric, multipurpose rounds. The round acts as both a fragmentation round and a high explosive/incendiary round, and was designed to defeat targets in confined shelters, behind natural barriers, and inside light vehicles.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->

<!-- This section is for grenade launchers -->
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon_gp-25">
		<text>GP-25 "Bonfire"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon_gp-25_s">
		<text>GP-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon_gp-25">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] VOG-25 rounds \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] VOG-25PM rounds \n \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] VG-40TB rounds \nThe GP-25 "Bonfire" (6G15) is a 40-mm caliber muzzle-loaded, rifled grenade launcher. Designed by V.N. Telesh and adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces in 1978. It is designed to be mounted on Kalashnikov assault rifles, and can be used to defeat targets in fortifications, in trenches, and on reverse slopes. Has an effective range from 100-400 meters. The complete equipment set comes with a rubber buttplate (mounted to the rifle's stock), and a special return spring guide with a receiver cover catch (for use on early-production rifles). \nIt is not recommended to mount grenade launchers on rifles with mounted optics and/or silencers due to violent recoil.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->

<!-- This section is for assault rifles and submachine guns -->
	<string id="wpn-colt1911_s">
		<text>Colt M1911 A1</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-akm">
		<text>AKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-akm_s">
		<text>AKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-akm">
		<text>7.62-mm modernized Kalashnikov assault rifle (6P1). The AKM was adopted in 1959 to replace the AK. The modernization process included lighter stamped components, increased effective range, reliability, and ease of use. The rifle can also mount newer muzzle brakes/silencers and grenade launchers. \nThe renowned Kalashnikov action ensures great reliability, and a great number of AKM variants are still in service with the Russian Army and MVD. \n%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm FMJ - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm API - armor-piercing incendiary</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-akms">
		<text>AKMS</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-oz33">
		<text>OZ-33 «Pernach»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-oz33_s">
		<text>OZ-33</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-oz33_desc">
		<text>9x18 mm automatic pistol OZ-33 «Pernach» is a russian pistol, which was developed in the mid of 1990s by group of designers of the Central Design Bureau of Sport and Hunting Weapons headed by Stechkin for APS pistol replacement. It was reviously known as AP SBZ-2 (automatic pistol designed by Stechkin, Baltzer, Zinchenko). Some of OZ-33 is used by various units of the Russian Ministry of Internal Affairs. Compared with "Stechkin" pistol OZ-33 has simplified design and improved handling.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-gsh18">
		<text>GSh-18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gsh18_desc">
		<text>9x19 mm selfloading pistol GSh-18 was developed in late 1990s in Instrument Design Bureau (Tula) by famous weapon designers (mainly guns for aircrafts) Gryazev and Shipunov. 18 is the capacity of the magazine. GSh-18 has fairly low weight, big magazine capacity, low profile barrel and good accuracy.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-akms_s">
		<text>AKMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-akms">
		<text>7.62-mm modernized Kalashnikov assault rifle with underfolding stock (6P4). The AKMS was adopted for the VDV and special units in 1959. The modernization process included lighter stamped components, increased effective range, reliability, and ease of use. The rifle can also mount newer muzzle brakes/silencers and grenade launchers. \nThe renowned Kalashnikov action ensures great reliability, and a great number of AKM variants are still in service with the Russian Army and MVD. \n%c[255,1,255,255]: %c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm FMJ - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm API - armor-piercing incendiary</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-akmsn">
		<text>AKMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-akmsn_s">
		<text>AKMS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-akmsn">
		<text>7.62-mm modernized Kalashnikov assault rifle with underfolding stock (6P4). The AKMS was adopted for the VDV and special units in 1959. The modernization process included lighter stamped components, increased effective range, reliability, and ease of use. The rifle can also mount newer muzzle brakes/silencers and grenade launchers. \nThe renowned Kalashnikov action ensures great reliability, and a great number of AKM variants are still in service with the Russian Army and MVD. \n%c[255,1,255,255]: %c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm FMJ - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm API - armor-piercing incendiary</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-akmsn3">
		<text>AKMSN3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-akmsn3_s">
		<text>AKMSN3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-akmsn3">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]: %c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm FMJ - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7.62x39 mm API - armor-piercing incendiary \n7.62-mm modernized Kalashnikov assault rifle with underfolding stock (6P4N). The AKMS was adopted for the VDV and special units in 1959. The modernization process included lighter stamped components, increased effective range, reliability, and ease of use. The rifle can also mount newer muzzle brakes/silencers and grenade launchers. \nThe renowned Kalashnikov action ensures great reliability, and a great number of AKM variants are still in service with the Russian Army and MVD. The "AKMSN" has a "dovetail" mount on the side of the receiver for mounting optics.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // --><!-- // --><!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ak74n">
		<text>AK74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak74n_s">
		<text>AK74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74n">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm EPR - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n5.45-mm Kalashnikov assault rifle (6P20). The AK74 was adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces in 1974, in connection with the transition to new, low-recoil cartridges. Compared to the AKM, the AK74 has a higher effective range and accuracy of fire. A significant innovation in the weapon's design was a two-chambered muzzle device, which serves as a muzzle brake, recoil compensator, and flash suppressor. \nThe renowned Kalashnikov action ensures great reliability, and a great number of AK74 variants are still in service with the Russian Army and MVD.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ak74n3">
		<text>AK74N3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak74n3_s">
		<text>AK74N3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74n3">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm EPR - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n5.45-mm Kalashnikov assault rifle (6P20N). The AK74 was adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces in 1974, in connection with the transition to new, low-recoil cartridges. Compared to the AKM, the AK74 has a higher effective range and accuracy of fire. A significant innovation in the weapon's design was a two-chambered muzzle device, which serves as a muzzle brake, recoil compensator, and flash suppressor. \nThe renowned Kalashnikov action ensures great reliability, and a great number of AK74 variants are still in service with the Russian Army and MVD. The "AK74N" has a "dovetail" mount on the side of the receiver for mounting optics.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-aks74ub">
		<text>AKS74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-aks74ub_s">
		<text>AKS74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-aks74ub">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm EPR - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n5.45-mm Kalashnikov compact assault rifle with a folding stock (6P26). The AKS74U is based on the AKS74 rifle, and designed for tank, artillery, and missile crews, as well as special forces. It was adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces and MVD in 1979. Compared with the AKS74 it has a shorter barrel and lower weight, leading to a decrease in effective range and accuracy of fire. \nA great number of AKS74U variants are still in service with the MVD and various security services.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-aks74ubn3">
		<text>AKS74UN3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-aks74ubn3_s">
		<text>AKS74UN3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-aks74ubn3">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm EPR - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.45x39 mm AP - armor-piercing \n5.45-mm Kalashnikov compact assault rifle with a folding stock (6P26N). The AKS74U is based on the AKS74 rifle, and designed for tank, artillery, and missile crews, as well as special forces. It was adopted by the Soviet Armed Forces and MVD in 1979. Compared with the AKS74 it has a shorter barrel and lower weight, leading to a decrease in effective range and accuracy of fire. \nA great number of AKS74U variants are still in service with the MVD and various security services. The "AKS74UN" has a "dovetail" mount on the side of the receiver for mounting optics.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ak102">
		<text>AK102-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak102_s">
		<text>AK102-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak102">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.56x45 mm FMJ - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.56x45 mm AP - armor-piercing \n5.56-mm Kalashnikov compact assault rifle (6P44-02). The AK101 is a modification of the AK74M for NATO-standard 5.56 ammunition, intended for export. Compared with the AK101, the AK102 has a shorter barrel and lower weight, leading to a decrease in effective range and accuracy of fire. The barrel is not as short as an AKS74U's, allowing for use of a full-length gas chamber and piston rod. The rifle also has a "dovetail" mount on the side of the receiver for mounting optics. "AK102-2" designation denotes a different firing mechanism allowing for 3-round bursts.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ak102_custom">
		<text>AK102-2 Custom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak102_custom_s">
		<text>AK102-2 Custom</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak102_custom">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.56x45 mm FMJ - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5.56x45 mm AP - armor-piercing \n
		%c[255,1,255,255]Equipped: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] ATG suppressor \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] tactical foregrip \n
		5.56-mm Kalashnikov compact assault rifle (6P44-02). The AK101 is a modification of the AK74M for NATO-standard 5.56 ammunition, intended for export. Compared with the AK101, the AK102 has a shorter barrel and lower weight, leading to a decrease in effective range and accuracy of fire. The barrel is not as short as an AKS74U's, allowing for use of a full-length gas chamber and piston rod. The rifle also has a "dovetail" mount on the side of the receiver for mounting optics. "AK102-2" designation (6P44-02)denotes a different firing mechanism allowing for 3-round bursts. This rifle has also been fitted with a custom upgrade kit, which includes a telescoping stock, a tactical handguard with a picatinny rail on the bottom, and an ergonomic foregrip.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->	
	<string id="wpn-ak105">
		<text>AK105-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-ak105_s">
		<text>AK105-2</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak105">
		<text>5.45-mm Kalashnikov compact assault rifle (6P47). Compared with the AK74M, the AK105 has a shorter barrel and lower weight, leading to a decrease in effective range and accuracy of fire. The barrel is not as short as an AKS74U's, allowing for use of a full-length gas chamber and piston rod. AK105-2 (6P47-02)denotes a different firing mechanism allowing for 3-round bursts. \n%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5,45õ39 mm EPR - standard \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 5,45õ39 mm AP - armor-piercing</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->	
	<string id="wpn-swd">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-swd_s">
		<text>SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-swd">
		<text>%c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7,62õ54 mm 7N1 - sniper \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7,62õ54 mm 7N26 - armor-piercing \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] 7,62õ54 mm 7N14 - sniper armor-piercing \n
		%c[255,1,255,255]Addons: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] TGP-V \n%c[255,1,255,255]• %c[default] butt cheek \n
		7.62-mm Dragunov self-loading sniper rifle (6V1). Designed to improve distance of effective firing for infantry. Main features - skeletal butt; gear and stamped receiver that derived from AK rifles; gas regulator for reliability in field operations. SVD is used world-wide in almost all combat operations as a reliable kind of weapon and one of the best self-loading sniper rifles. Main deficiency of SVD is  big length.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->	
	
	
<!-- This section is for silencers -->
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_pbs1">
		<text>PBS-1 silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_pbs1_s">
		<text>PBS-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-addon-silencer_pbs1">
		<text>PBS-1 silencer (6Ch12). Designed for noiseless and flameless fire from 7.62-mm Kalashnikov rifles. Developed by NII-61 (now TsNIITochMash) and adopted in 1962 for the Soviet army's reconnaisance, sabotage, and special-purpose units. Replaces the standard muzzle brake. If using this silencer, subsonic (7.62x39 US) rounds must be used.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_pbs4">
		<text>PBS-4 silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_pbs4_s">
		<text>PBS-4</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-addon-silencer_pbs4">
		<text>PBS-4 silencer. Developed by NII-61 (now TsNIITochMash) and adopted in 1980 for the Soviet army's reconnaisance, sabotage, and special-purpose units. Designed for noiseless and flameless fire from the AKS74U, as part of the "Canary" (6S1) complex with a silent grenade launcher. Replaces the standard muzzle brake. Can be installed on the AKS74U and its variants. If using this silencer, subsonic (5.45x39 US) rounds must be used.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_tgp-a">
		<text>TGP-A silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_tgp-a_s">
		<text>TGP-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-addon-silencer_tgp-a">
		<text>TGP-A silencer/flash suppressor. Designed to muffle firing sound and suppress muzzle flash on 5.45-mm Kalashnikov rifles. Replaces the standard muzzle device.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_atg">
		<text>ATG silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_atg_s">
		<text>ATG</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-addon-silencer_atg">
		<text>ATG tactical silencer for assault rifles. Reduces the loudness and visible manifestation of shooting from 5,56-mm Kalashnikov rifles. Can be mounted in place of muzzle compensator.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_tgp-v">
		<text>TGP-V silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer_tgp-v_s">
		<text>TGP-V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-addon-silencer_tgp-v">
		<text>TGP-V tactical silencer for assault rifles. Can be used for position masking (almost no flare) and reducing sound impact to the user during firing from 7,62-mm Dragunov sniper rifle. Can be mounted to default SVD flame arrestor.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->

<!-- This section is for optics -->
<!-- // -->
 	<string id="addon_scope_acog"> <!-- îïèñàíèå åñòü â ÎÃÑÅ, çàìåíÿåì -->
		<text>ACOG scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_acog_s">
		<text>ACOG</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_acog"> <!-- îïèñàíèå åñòü â ÎÃÑÅ, çàìåíÿåì -->
		<text>Trijicon ACOG® (Advanced Combat Optical Gunsight) scope. Does not require batteries - reticle illumination is done via optical fibers (tritium illumination is used in low-light conditions). Designed to be mounted on standard NATO picatinny rails. 4x magnification.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_susat">
		<text>SUSAT L9A1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_susat_s">
		<text>SUSAT L9A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_susat">
		<text>SUSAT L9A1 (Sight Unit, Small Arms, Trilux) scope. Tritium illumination is used in low-light conditions. Its integrated mount is designed for the L85 rifle. 4x magnification.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_pso1">
		<text>PSO-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_pso1_s">
		<text>PSO-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_pso1">
		<text>PSO-1 (6Ts1) sniper scope. Designed for aimed fire in day or night conditions, at illuminated or backlit targets. The sight features a rangefinder grind, allowing for range estimation based on horizontal measurements. The design and housing bracket allows the optic to be installed on any weapon with SVD-like "dovetail" mount. 4x magnification.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_1p29">
		<text>USP-1 "Tulip" scope</text>

	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_1p29_s">
		<text>USP-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_1p29">
		<text>USP-1 "Tulip" (1P29) unified combat scope. Designed for aimed fire in day or night conditions, at illuminated or backlit targets. Does not require batteries (tritium illumination is used in low-light conditions). The design and housing bracket allows the optic to be installed on any weapon with a Soviet-standard "dovetail" mount. 4x magnification.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_kobra">
		<text>EKP "Kobra" sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_kobra_s">
		<text>EKP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_kobra">
		<text>EKP "Kobra" open collimator sight with electronic controls for brightness and reticle type. It was designed to improve the speed of shooting at emerging and moving targets, in daylight or low-light conditions. The design and housing bracket allows the optic to be installed on any weapon with a Soviet-standard "dovetail" mount.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_1pn51">
		<text>NSPU-3 "Cassowary" scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_1pn51_s">
		<text>NSPU-3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_1pn51">
		<text>NSPU-3 (1PN51) unified night-vision gunsight. Designed for battlefield observation and aimed fire from lightweight small arms in daylight or low-light conditions. The design and housing bracket allows the optic to be installed on any weapon with a Soviet-standard "dovetail" mount. 3.46x magnification</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_eotech">
		<text>EOTech 552.A65 sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_eotech_s">
		<text>EOTech 552.A65</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_eotech">
		<text>L-3 EOTech 552.A65 Military Series weapon sight (Holographic Weapon Sight, sight mark is formed as a result of difraction of laser radiation on the hologram). Was designed for mounting on the standard NATO mount - Picatinny rail. Can be used together with optical magnifiers. Has lower bright mode for using with night vision devices.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_1p59">
		<text>«Hyperon» scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_1p59_s">
		<text>«Hyperon»</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_1p59">
		<text>Pancratic sniper scope «Hyperon» (1P59). Was designed for sniper firing during day and night. Provides automatic input of the aiming angle when measuring distance to the target. Can be attached on the standard Soviet mount - "dovetail" side rail.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_pso1-1">
		<text>PSO-1M2-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_pso1-1_s">
		<text>PSO-1M2-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_pso1-1">
		<text>Optical sniper scope PSO-1M2-1. Was designed for sniper firing during day and night. Has specific range grid that allows to account horizontal corrections. Can be attached on the standard Soviet mount - "dovetail" side rail. 4x magnification.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_mtk83">
		<text>MTK-83 optic base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_mtk83_s">
		<text>MTK-83</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_mtk83">
		<text>MTK-83 bracket adapter - a device for installing picatinny rail-mounted optics on weapons with a Soviet "dovetail" mount. The design of the bracket allows for quick detachment and reattachment without losing zero.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_side_rail">
		<text>"Dovetail" optic base</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_scope_side_rail_s">
		<text>"Dovetail"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_side_rail">
		<text>"Dovetail" side mount - a device for installing Warsaw Pact scopes. The design allows for quick detachment and reattachment without losing zero.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->

<!-- This section is for magazines -->
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_akm30">
		<text>30-round AKM magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_akm30_s">
		<text>30: 7.62x39 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_akm30">
		<text>7.62x39 mm double-stack box magazine, 30-round capacity for the AKM (6L10). Interchangeable with 40-round box magazines and 75-round drum magazines. Compatible with whole line of AKM-series assault carbines.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_rpk40">
		<text>40-round RPK magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_rpk40_s">
		<text>40: 7.62x39 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_rpk40">
		<text>7.62x39 mm double-stack box magazine, 40-round capacity for the RPK. Interchangeable with 30-round (6L10) box magazines and 75-round drum magazines. Compatible with whole line of AKM-series assault carbines.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_rpk75">
		<text>75-round RPK drum magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_rpk75_s">
		<text>75: 7.62x39 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_rpk75">
		<text>7.62x39 mm drum magazine, 75-round capacity for the RPK. Interchangeable with 40-round and 30-round (6L10) box magazines. Compatible with whole line of AKM-series assault carbines.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_ak7430">
		<text>30-round AK74 magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_ak7430_s">
		<text>30: 5.45x39 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_ak7430">
		<text>5.45x39 mm double-stack box magazine, 30-round capacity for the AK74 (6L20). Interchangeable with 45-round (6L18) and 60-round (6L31) box magazines. Compatible with whole line of AK74-series assault carbines.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_rpk7445">
		<text>45-round RPK74 magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_rpk7445_s">
		<text>45: 5.45x39 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_rpk7445">
		<text>5.45x39 mm double-stack box magazine, 45-round capacity for the RPK74 (6L18). Interchangeable with 30-round (6L20) and 60-round (6L31) box magazines. Compatible with whole line of AK74-series assault carbines.</text>
	</string>
	<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_ak10560">
		<text>60-round AK74M/AK105 magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_ak10560_s">
		<text>60: 5.45x39 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_ak10560">
		<text>5.45x39 mm quad-stack box magazine, 60-round capacity for the AK74M and AK105 (6L31). Interchangeable with 30-round (6L20) and 45-round (6L18) box magazines. Compatible with whole line of AK74-series assault carbines.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_ak10230">
		<text>30-round AK101/AK102 magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_ak10230_s">
		<text>30: 5.56x45 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_ak10230">
		<text>5.56x45 mm box magazine, 30-round capacity for the AK101 and AK102 (6L29). Made of fiberglass-reinforced plastic with steel feed lips and locking lug.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_cmag100">
		<text>100-round Beta C-Mag magazine</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_cmag100_s">
		<text>100: 5.56x45 mm</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_cmag100">
		<text>Beta C-Mag magazine with 100 5.56x45 mm cartridges. Developed by Jim Sullivan. Made of plastic reinforced with glass fiber, equipped with metal neck and cover. The latest version of the magazine is available with a transparent backing to allow the user to see the number of rounds remaining in the magazine.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_svd10">
		<text>SVD clip</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_svd10_s">
		<text>10: 7.62x54 ìì</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_svd10">
		<text>Box magazine of selector type with two rows of 10 7.62x54 mm cartridges, placed in checkboard pattern.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_mag_svd20">
		<text>SVU-A clip</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_mag_svd20_s">
		<text>20: 7.62x54 ìì</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_mag_svd20">
		<text>Experimental box magazine of selector type with two rows of 20 7.62x54 mm cartridges, placed in checkboard pattern. Compatible with full-sized SVD rifle.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->

<!-- This section is for grips/handguards -->
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_gip">
		<text>Tactical foregrip</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_gip_s">
		<text>Foregrip</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_gip">
		<text>A tactical foregrip, which can be installed on NATO-standard picatinny rails.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_ak100_custom">
		<text>Custom AK Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_ak100_custom_s">
		<text>Custom ÀÊ Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_ak100_custom">
		<text>Custom ÀÊ Kit for 10x serie of Kalashnikov rifles. Includes telescopic butt, pistol anatomic handgrip and handguard with lower standard NATO mount (Picatinny rail).</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_gp_galoscha">
		<text>UGL backplate</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_gp_galoscha_s">
		<text>UGL backplate/shock absorber</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_gp_galoscha">
		<text>Backplate/shock absorber for underbarrel grenade launcher. Reduces recoil during firing from grenade launcher. Can be attached to the butt of the rifle and fixed with strap.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_svd_scheek">
		<text>Cheek for SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_svd_scheek_s">
		<text>Cheek for SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_svd_scheek">
		<text>Unadjustable cheek rest, can be attached on SVD. Makes sniper fire management more convenient. Can be mounted on the butt and fixed on it with a lock.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_usp_ck9">
		<text>HK 9mm Conversion Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_usp_ck9_s">
		<text>HK 9mm CK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_usp_ck45">
		<text>HK .45 Caliber Conversion Kit</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_usp_ck45_s">
		<text>HK .45 CK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_usp_ck">
		<text>Heckler&Koch Conversion Kit is designed for switching of USP pistol caliber with new barrel, magazine and shutter.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_bino">
		<text>B10õ42</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_bino_s">
		<text>Bunoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_bino">
		<text>Army 10x binoculars B10õ42 "Gloss".</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_bino_nv">
		<text>Yukon NVB Tracker</text>
	</string>
	<string id="addon_bino_nv_s">
		<text>NV binoculars</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_bino_nv">
		<text>Binoculars with night vision Yukon NVB Tracker.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="st_tail_desc">
		<text>rail</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_mag_desc">
		<text>mag.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grip_desc">
		<text>grip</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
