<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251" ?>
<string_table>
<!-- ching chang chong nip nong -->
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>9ı18mm PM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-fmj_s">
		<text>9ı18 PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-fmj">
		<text>9ı18 PM. Simple full metal jacket bullet with a steel core. Weak armor penetration. Probably the most widespread type of ammunition in the Zone.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pbp">
		<text>9x18mm PBM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pbp_s">
		<text>9x18 PBM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pbp">
		<text>9ı18 PBM - Further development of the standard issue 9ı18mm cartridge with enhanced armor penetration. Hollow-point bullet with a steel core.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>9x18mm PMM rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x18-pmm_s">
		<text>9ı18 PMM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x18-pmm">
		<text>The military was looking forward extending the life of the standard soviet 9x18mm pistol round, which resulted in creation of the PMM variant. It boasts enhanced ballistic parameters. Due to higher muzzle velocity and use of a steel core, it's much more efficient than the standard cartridge. The armor penetration capabilities have been hugely improved.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>9x19mm Parabellum rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-fmj_s">
		<text>9ı19 FMJ</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-fmj">
		<text>Standard issue 9x19mm Luger/Parabellum cartridge in use by NATO forces, with a standard full metal jacket bullet. Weak armor penetration.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>9x19mm Dum-Dum rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x19-pbp_s">
		<text>9x19 DD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x19-pbp">
		<text>Handcrafted 9x19mm Luger/Parabellum cartridge. This round boasts a copper bullet with a lead core which flattens itself on impact, resulting in frightening wounds. Frivolous use of such ammunition often resulted in the barrel getting clogged up with lead and the soft bullet tip was often a cause of many misfires. The bullet flight trajectory has also been negatively affected and armor penetration remains pretty weak.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>5.45x39mm 7N6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-fmj_s">
		<text>5.45x39 7N6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-fmj">
		<text>Standard issue intermediate cartridge for assault rifles produced in the 70s for the Soviet Army. Full metal jacket bullet with a steel core. Its stopping power and armor penetration aren't sensational in any way.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>5.45x39mm 7N22 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.45x39-ap_s">
		<text>5.45x39 7N22</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.45x39-ap">
		<text>Armor-piercing variant of the standard 5.45x39mm round. This cartridge boasts a bullet with a high-carbon steel core. Supporters of the 5.45 round claim that with the new armor-piercing round, their weapons are just as efficient in combat as weapons chambered for 7.62.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>5.56x45mm SS109 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ss190_s">
		<text>5.56x45 SS109</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ss190">
		<text>5.56ı45mm NATO, SS109. Standard issue intermediate NATO rifle cartridge with a full metal jacket bullet. This particular variant is of Belgian origin.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>5.56x45mm M995 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-5.56x45-ap_s">
		<text>5.56x45 M995</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-5.56x45-ap">
		<text>5.56ı45mm M995. Armor-piercing variant of the standard issue NATO rifle cartridge, sporting a bullet with a tungsten core.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N1 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h1_s">
		<text>7.62x54R 7N1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h1">	
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N1 - Standard issue sniper rifle cartridge with a heavy (long-range) soft-point bullet intented for use in big game hunting.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N13 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-ap_s">
		<text>7.62x54R 7N13</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-ap">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N13 - Armor-piercing variant of the standard issue sniper rifle cartridge.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N14 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x54-7h14_s">
		<text>7.62x54R 7N14</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x54-7h14">
		<text>7.62x54mmR 7N14 - A sniper variant of the standard issue sniper rifle cartridge. Its effective range and accuracy have been improved.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-gauss">
		<text>2x10mm M62 cartridges</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-gauss_s">
		<text>2ı10 M62</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-gauss">
		<text>Custom cartridge for the Gauss gun (Project 62). It represents a combination of a battery which contains concentrated electric charges with a magazine which contains lethal ammunition made of a special material. The energy source is an encapsulated fragment of the "Flash" artefact while the ferromagnetic projectile is a tungsten rod of a relatively small diameter.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>9x39mm PAB-9 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-pab9_s">
		<text>9ı39 PAB-9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-pab9">
		<text>9x39mm - Russian subsonic rifle cartridge. The PAB-9 variant which boasts a bullet with a tempered steel core was an attempt to reduce the production costs of the armor-piercing SP-6 round. The poorly conceived development of this round makes its use very risky, as the weapons utilizing it are more prone to jamming than they typically are.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>9x39mm SP-6 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-9x39-ap_s">
		<text>9x39 SP-6</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-9x39-ap">
		<text>9ı39mm - Armor-piercing variant of the russian subsonic rifle round. The heavy bullet produces no supersonic shockwave during flight, making it noiseless. Allows for penetration of body armor up to 350 meters.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>11.43x23mm rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-fmj_s">
		<text>.45 ACP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-fmj">
		<text>.45 ACP - Automatic Colt Pistol, 11.43x23mm. This cartridge boasts a heavy steel bullet with a lead core, as well as a relatively weak powder charge. This combination resulted in pretty low flight velocity, but it's balanced out by good accuracy and sufficient stopping power.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>11.43x23mm Hydra-Shok rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-11.43x23-hydro_s">
		<text>.45 HYDRA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-11.43x23-hydro">
		<text>The "Hydra-Shok" variant of the .45 ACP ammunition sports a jacketed hollow point bullet with a flat tip. This cartridge offers good stopping power due to reliable expansion and deeper penetration of organic tissues.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>12x70mm buckshot rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-buck_s">
		<text>12ı70 BUCK</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x70-buck">
		<text>A standard 12 caliber round filled with buckshot. It has an enormous killing power at a close range. It is most effective at ranges under 30 meters.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>12x76mm slug rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x76-zhekan_s">
		<text>12x76 SLUG</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x76-zhekan">
		<text>A round with a heavy bullet. It is intended for big game hunting, but that doesn't stop anyone for using it on something else. Its heavy bullet does not pierce but actually forces itself through bulletproof vests.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-12x70-kart">
		<text>12x76mm buckshot rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-12x70-kart_s">
		<text>12x76 BUCK.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-12x70-kart">
		<text>A standard 12 caliber round filled with buckshot. It has an enormous killing power at a close range. It is most effective at ranges under 30 meters.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p">
		<text>7.62x25mm P rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-p_s">
		<text>7.62x25 P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x25-p">
		<text>7.62x25 P. Pistol cartridge boasting a full metal jacket bullet with a lead core.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps">
		<text>7.62x25mm PS rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x25-ps_s">
		<text>7.62x25 PS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x25-ps">
		<text>7.62x25mm PS. Pistol cartridge with improved armor-piercing capabilities, boasting a bullet with a steel core.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39-fmj">
		<text>7.62x39mm M43 rounds</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-7.62x39-fmjs">
		<text>7.62ı39 M43</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x39-fmj">
		<text>7.62ı39mm, M43 variant. Soviet-era assault rifle cartridge with a full metal jacket bullet.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39-ap">
		<text>7.62x39mm AP rounds</text>
	</string>
    <string id="ammo-7.62x39-aps">
		<text>7.62ı39 AP</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-7.62x39-ap">
		<text>7.62ı39mm AP. Armor-piercing variant of the Soviet-era assault rifle cartridge.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-og-7b">
		<text>TBG-7V warhead</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-og-7b_s">
		<text>TBG-7V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-og-7b">
		<text>Multi-purpose thermobaric warhead for the RPG-7V. It is equally effective against troops and light armored vehicles. Blast radius - 10 meters.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-m209">
		<text>40mm M406 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m209_s">
		<text>40MM M406</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m209">
		<text>40mm M406. High-explosive fragmentation grenade for the M203 grenade launcher.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-m208a">
		<text>40mm HEAB grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-m208a_s">
		<text>40MM HEAB</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-m208a">
		<text>HEAB (High Explosive Air Bursting). High-explosive fragmentation grenade with remote detonation function, for rifles equipped with grenade launchers combined with electronic targeting systems (XM8, FN2000). With enough skill, it is possible to take down aerial targets.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo_atom">
		<text>40mm ATOM grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo_atom_s">
		<text>40MM ATOM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-atom">
		<text>Nuclear charge packed in a standard 40mm grenade, compatible with most western grenade launchers. Nobody knows who produces this type of ammunition, let alone where. How Monolith got their hands on such grenade - nobody knows. Usable only with rifles equipped with grenade launchers combined with electronic targeting systems.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-vog-25">
		<text>VOG-25 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25_s">
		<text>VOG-25</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25">
		<text>Fragmentation grenade intended for use in eastern-made grenade launchers.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-vog-25p">
		<text>VOG-25P grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-vog-25p_s">
		<text>VOG-25P</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-vog-25p">
		<text>Fragmentation grenade intended for use in eastern-made grenade launchers. Prior to explosion, the grenade leaps up about one meter increasing its damaging effect.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ammo-arbolt">
		<text>Crossbow bolt</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-arbolt">
		<text>A bolt intended for use in hunting crossbows. Aluminium arrow with plastic feathers and a sharp tip with 3 blades made of high-carbon steel. Guaranteed kill on unarmoured targets.</text>
    </string>
<!-- // -->	
	<string id="ammo_flame">
		<text>Flamethrower fuel</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo_flame_s">
		<text>FUEL</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_flame">
		<text>Two-component gas mixture for the Flamethrower. It consists of a gas labelled with the letter "F" and oil combined with white phosphorus to allow spontaneous combustion in the air.</text>
	</string>	
<!-- V etoy sekcii raspolojeny dva navesnyh podstvol'nyh granatometa -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
		<text>GP-25 "Kostyor"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher">
		<text>Under-barrel mounted grenade launcher for AK family rifles. A quick and efficient way to send explosive death to multiple enemies at once in a ten meter radius, which makes it very useful. \n Ammunition:\n VOG-25 \n VOG-25P.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
		<text>M203</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-grenade-launcher-m203">
		<text>Under-barrel mounted M203 grenade launcher - Single shot, reload functions by moving the barrel forward and replacing the spent shell with a new one. Usable only on NATO rifles. \n Ammunition:\n 40mm M406.</text>
	</string>
<!-- V etoy sekcii raspolojena vsyakaya hren' navrode vzryvayuschihsya bochek -->
	<string id="Ammo">
		<text>Ammunition</text>
	</string>
    <string id="fuelcan">
		<text>Fuel can</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bomba">
		<text>Fuel bomb</text>
	</string>
    <string id="bochka">
		<text>Fuel tank</text>
	</string>
    <string id="kanistra">
		<text>Cannister</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_kanistra">
		<text>A cannister, filled up with something explosive. You can pick it up, leave it anywhere you want and with a few shots, blow it up from a safe distance.</text>
	</string>
    <string id="dinamito">
		<text>Dynamite</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_explosive_bomba">
		<text>A wonderful tool to use when you want to get rid of your enemies from a distance. Shooting this thing will bring pain and destruction to everything and everyone within 8 meters.</text>
	</string>
<!-- Dalee sleduet strelkovoe orujie v poryadke includ'ov v fayle weapons.ltx -->
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn_hpsa">
		<text>Browning HP-SA</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-hpsa">
		<text>Browning Hi-Power pistol. It deserves to be considered as one of the best pistols of the 20th century, thanks to its reliability and sufficient stopping power.\n Ammunition:\n 9x19mm FMJ \n 9x19mm DD </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn_tt">
		<text>Tula-Tokarev TT-33</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_tt_short">
		<text>TT-33</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_tt">
		<text>The TT-33 - Veteran of the Great Patriotic War. For its days, the TT pistol used to be considered as a perfect companion of a Red Army soldier, thanks to its almost unrivaled reliability as well as easy maintenance and repair. Its biggest problems were the tricky safety switch, inadequate stopping power of the light 7.62 cartridge and a rather uncomfortable grip.\n Ammunition:\n 7.62x25mm P \n 7.62x25mm PS </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-pm">
		<text>Makarov PM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pm">
		<text>Standard sidearm of the Ukrainian military, in service for god knows how many years. It doesn't offer much stopping power or accuracy, but its small size allows you to keep it hidden in your jacket without any problems, but there's nothing you can hope for in a real battle, although its reliability and ease of use and maintenance remains unrivaled.\n Ammunition:\n 9x18mm PM \n 9x18mm PBM \n 9x18mm PMM </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-pb">
		<text>PB/6P9</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pb">
		<text>A silenced pistol based on the Makarov PM, built for military reconnaisance units and the KGB personnel. Nowadays obsolete, but still very dangerous in the hands of a skilled soldier.\n Ammunition:\n 9x18mm PM \n 9x18mm PBM \n 9x18mm PMM </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn_usp">
		<text>HK USP</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-usp">
		<text>A solid piece of quality German engineering - The USP, a compact pistol designed for close-quarters combat. It's pretty popular among hardened veterans of the Zone.\n Ammunition:\n 11.43x23mm FMJ \n 11.43x23mm Hydra-Shok </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-fort">
		<text>Fort-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fort">
		<text>The standard sidearm of the Ukrainian military. Its ergonomics are a vast improvement over the Makarov PM, as well as its accuracy, recoil and rate of fire. It's also noticeably larger and heavier.\n Ammunition:\n 9x18mm PM \n 9x18mm PBM \n 9x18mm PMM </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-fort_m">
		<text>Fort-15</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fort_m1">
		<text>Experimental prototype of the Fort pistol with a more capacious magazine.\n Ammunition:\n 9x18mm PM \n 9x18mm PBM \n 9x18mm PMM </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-colt1911">
		<text>Colt M1911A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-colt1911">
		<text>An All-American masterpiece, which appeared in all the conflicts of the 20th century and entered the new century with confidence. Its small-size magazine is partially compensated by the use of a high-powered round which literally liberates the brains out of its targets.\n Ammunition:\n 11.43x23mm FMJ \n 11.43x23mm Hydra-Shok </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-colt_m1">
		<text>Silenced Colt M1911A1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-colt_m1">
		<text>The old good M1911, sporting a non-detachable silencer. Weapon of hired assassins, who suffer from dementia and also a hangover, because obviously you can't be serious when you use a gun like that to conduct business. Well, at least the ammo is strong enough to punch through a brick wall.\n Ammunition:\n 11.43x23mm FMJ \n 11.43x23mm Hydra-Shok </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-beretta">
		<text>Beretta 92FS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-beretta">
		<text>The Beretta 92FS is considered to be a fairly reliable but somewhat cumbersome pistol. The main target of criticism is its enormous grip which is only comfortable if you have very large hands, if you don't mind the gun itself being big enough.\n Ammunition:\n 9x19mm FMJ \n 9x19mm DD </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wp_desert_eagle">
		<text>Magnum Research Desert Eagle</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-desert-eagle">
		<text>A real gun for real heroes. It is big, heavy and powerful as all hell. It is not very popular in the Zone due to its price and size. After all, you don't go hunting for elephants every day.\n Ammunition:\n 11.43x23mm FMJ \n 11.43x23mm Hydra-Shok </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-eagle_m1">
		<text>Desert Eagle Mark XIX</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-eagle_m1">
		<text>A gun that is already powerful, reworked to fit 9x39mm bullets. Absolutely overkill for close-range combat. If you value your eardrums, don't fire this gun, ever. There's one question about it - How the hell did these bullets fit in? Looking closely at this gun, it becomes clear that the entire frame as well as the handle have been designed from scratch to sport a bigger magazine. Clearly the gunsmith was smoking some real good stuff.\n Ammunition:\n 9x39mm PAB-9 \n 9x39mm SP-6 </text>
	</string>
<!-- V etoy sekcii nahodyatsya shturmovye vintovki i PP -->
	<string id="wpn-ak47">
		<text>¿ M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak47">
		<text>Of all the weapons in the vast soviet arsenal, nothing was more profitable than Avtomat Kalashnikova model of 1947. More commonly known as the AK, or Kalashnikov. It's the world's most popular assault rifle. A weapon all fighters love. An elegantly simple 9 pound amalgamation of forged steel and plywood. It doesn't break, jam, or overheat. It'll shoot whether it's covered in mud or filled with sand. It's so easy, even a child can use it, and they do. Since the end of the Cold War, the Kalashnikov has become the Russian people's greatest export. After that comes vodka, caviar, and suicidal novelists. One thing is for sure, no one was lining up to buy their cars.\n Ammunition:\n 7.62x39mm M43 \n 7.62x39mm AP </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->

	<string id="wpn-ak74">
		<text>AKS-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74">
		<text>Standard Kalashnikov assault rifle with a folding stock, chambered for a more lightweight intermediate cartridge, 5.45. Despite the emergence of more advanced weaponry in the nineties, it's still prevalent among many armies around the world, thanks to its almost unrivaled efficiency and reliability.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ak74u">
		<text>AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74u">
		<text>A compact variant of the Kalashnikov assault rifle, with a folding stock. If you don't mind trading off accuracy for smaller size, it's a good gun. It's more difficult to control than the standard Kalashnikov rifles, but at least it supports the most prevalent intermediate cartridge in the Zone - 5.45. Its another advantage is its pretty large magazine.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ak74_m1">
		<text>Modified AKS-74</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74_m1">
		<text>AKS-74. The modified closing mechanism (lightweight bolt carrier and a hardened return spring) has increased the gun's rate of fire.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ak74u_m1">
		<text>AKS-74UB Spetsnaz</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ak74u_m1">
		<text>AKS-74UB. A modified variant of the standard compact assault rifle with a non-detachable silencer.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-aks74_m1_camo1">
		<text>Camouflaged AKS-74 "Cobra"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74_m1_camo1">
		<text>Modified AKS-74 assault rifle, fitted with a "Cobra" holographic sight. It sports a camouflage pattern for whatever reason, perhaps in a futile attempt to make both the gun and the user less noticeable.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-aks74u_m1_camo1">
		<text>Assault AKS-74U</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_aks74u_m1_camo1">
		<text>Modified AKS-74U compact assault rifle, fitted with a "Cobra" holographic sight and sporting a camouflage pattern. The extended barrel makes it possible to attach the GP-25 "Kostyor" grenade launcher.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-groza">
		<text>SGK OTs-14-4A "Groza"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza">
		<text>Strelkovo-Granatomyotnyi Kompleks OTs-14-4A "Groza" - A magnificent modular bullpup assault rifle which is compact, reliable and very powerful, with the power factor multiplied further by the under-barrel grenade launcher. A single trigger controls both the grenade launcher and the rifle itself, with a separate barrel selector. The rifle also allows for mounting a rifle scope. A very efficient gun, favoured especially by military Stalkers.\n Ammunition:\n 9x39mm PAB-9 \n 9x39mm SP-6 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-groza_m1">
		<text>SGK OTs-14-4A "Groza" 5.45</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-groza_m1">
		<text>Strelkovo-Granatomyotnyi Kompleks OTs-14-4A "Groza". This particular weapon is a work of art, made by an exceptionally skilled gunsmith who managed to modify this rifle to support 5.45 intermediate ammunition which is more prevalent in the Zone than the subsonic 9x39 ammunition. The 7N22 variant makes this gun just as deadly as an AKM.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-val">
		<text>AS Val</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-val">
		<text>The AS Val is a weapon designed specifically for the Russian Spetsnaz. It is similar in function and construction to the VSS Vintorez, to the point where both guns share 70% of their parts. The main differences between this gun and the VSS are the bigger magazine and a folding stock. The main focus of the Val was to provide fully automatic fire with almost zero noise. This weapon allows the user to pierce virtually any bulletproof vest or a helmet at a distance of up to 400 meters while not giving the shooter's position away.\n Ammunition:\n 9x39mm PAB-9 \n 9x39mm SP-6 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-val_m1">
		<text>Scoped AS Val</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-val_m1">
		<text>Slightly modified AS Val rifle. This weapon sports a high-magnification rifle scope which turns it pretty much into a VSS with a bigger magazine.\n Ammunition:\n 9x39mm PAB-9 \n 9x39mm SP-6 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-fn2000">
		<text>FN Herstal F2000</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-fn2000">
		<text>The Belgian F2000 modular bullpup assault rifle with a proprietary FN EGLM grenade launcher. What makes this gun special is a computerized fire control system which includes a laser rangefinder as well as a trajectory and ballistics calculator.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-g36">
		<text>HK G36</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-g36">
		<text>The German Heckler und Koch G36 assault rifle. Used as a main service rifle by the German Bundeswehr, as well as the Spanish army and the British police. The G36 is probably the first-grade specimen of modern weaponry: lightweight, efficient, patented, made of plastic and heinously overpriced. There's one unsolved mystery though - how the hell did that rifle end up in the Zone in the first place? That gun is exported only with permission of the German government with a sickening load of background checks, there's no way it could arrive in Ukraine legally.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-m16a1">
		<text>AR-15</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_m16a1">
		<text>The all-American AR-15 assault rifle, chambered for 5.56 ammunition. One of the most widespread firearms in the world. The ultimate rival of Kalashnikov's AK, beating it down in single-shot accuracy, ergonomy and modularity. However, even after all the attempts to modernize the AR-15 line, it's still a very demanding weapon which requires regular cleaning and maintenance.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-sig550">
		<text>SIG SG 550 (Stgw.90)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig550">
		<text>Swiss SG 550 assault rifle, produced by Swiss Arms AG. Its accuracy, high reliability and overall quality have earned it quite a following and it's the standard service rifle of the Swiss Army for all the aforementioned reasons. To decrease the weight and size of the rifle, some of its parts such as the foregrip, stock and the 20 or 30 round magazines are made of plastic, with the slight exception of the magazines since some of them are translucent. Overall, the SG 550 family of rifles is a force to be reckoned with.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-sig_m1">
		<text>SIG SG 550 (Kurz)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig_m1">
		<text>Standard SG 550 assault rifle turned into a carbine rifle, with barrel length shortened to a whooping 360 millimeters. These modifications will prove useful in urban warfare. Some internal components have been removed as a drastic measure of weight reduction, making it impossible to mount a grenade launcher, but at least the gun is lighter than before.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-sig_m2">
		<text>SIG SG 550 (Ersatz-Sniper)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-sig_m2">
		<text>An effort of the Zone's gunsmiths to turn an assault rifle into an automatic sniper rifle. This gun is equipped with an unremovable optical sight with increased magnification.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn_mac10">
		<text>Ingram MAC-10</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-mac10">
		<text>Compact American machine pistol. The company's goal was to design a weapon which is incredibly simple to use, maintain and cheap to produce. Since this short gun utilizes powerful ammunition, its recoil and spread are directly proportional to the firepower, as expected of the .45 cartridge. Hip firing at anything that's farther than 25 meters away is a guaranteed miss.\n Ammunition:\n 11.43x23mm FMJ \n 11.43x23mm Hydra-Shok </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn_mac10_m1">
		<text>Ingram MAC-10 "Leon"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-mac10_m1">
		<text>Modified variant of the MAC-10 machine pistol, nicknamed "Leon". The non-detachable silencer and increased magazine make it quite admirable.\n Ammunition:\n 11.43x23mm FMJ \n 11.43x23mm Hydra-Shok </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-mp5">
		<text>HK MP5</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5">
		<text>Heckler und Koch MP5 sub-machine gun, based on the G3 assault rifle. Widely used by various police and military forces of many countries in Europe and other continents as well. Eventually the MP5 became probably the most common and recognizable sub-machine gun in the world. The factors which contributed to MP5's success are its relatively compact size, ease of use, high accuracy and an adequately powerful cartridge. Its reliability is stuff legends are made of. When it was gradually replaced with more up-to-date models or newer sub-machine guns, it appeared on the black market, and ended up in the Zone.\n Ammunition:\n 9x19mm FMJ \n 9x19mm DD </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-mp5_m1">
		<text>HK MP5 9x18</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5_m1">
		<text>Standard Heckler und Koch MP5 sub-machine gun, modified to utilize 9x18 ammunition. Lightweight, compact, compatible with the most prevalent pistol cartridge in the Zone. This sub-machine gun is a marvelous find for any novice Stalker.\n Ammunition:\n 9x18mm PM \n 9x18mm PBM \n 9x18mm PMM </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-mp5_m2">
		<text>HK MP5SD3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-mp5_m2">
		<text>Heckler und Koch MP5SD3. This particular model came equipped with a non-detachable integral suppressor. Other than being quiet, it shares pretty much all advantages and disadvantages of the standard MP5.\n Ammunition:\n 9x19mm FMJ \n 9x19mm DD </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-mp40">
		<text>Schmeisser MP 40</text>
	</string>
	<string id="arsenal_mod-mp40">
		<text>MP 40, a WWII relic which used to be the German Army's standard sub-machine gun. Apparently designed to be utilized by airborne troops and tankers as well, since it comes with a folding stock. The MP 40 proved to be a quite successful construction and thus it entered mass production. Its main advantages were compact size for its time, easy handling and adequate reliability. Its main disadvantage was the cartridge. The 9x19 ammunition couldn't reach optimal muzzle velocity which affected flatness of the trajectory. Somewhat common in the Zone after a group of diggers found an old munitions bunker with lots of old weapons and gun oil stocked in it. Most of the found guns were in almost untouched condition and thus they got quickly sold out.\n Ammunition:\n 9x19mm FMJ \n 9x19mm DD </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-ppsh41">
		<text>Shpagin PPSh-41</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-ppsh41">
		<text>PPSh-41 sub-machine gun, designed by Georgy Shpagin, chambered for TT ammunition. Adopted by the USSR in 1941 and used extensively in World War II, as well as in other armed conflicts. The PPSh is a fairly simple and reliable weapon, which thanks to its very high rate of fire and an incredibly capacious drum magazine, performs exceptionally well in close quarters combat. The main disadvantage is the magazine loading process, which due to its capacity, is very time-consuming. Pretty common in the Zone after a group of diggers found an old munitions bunker with lots of surprisingly well-maintained old weapons and gun oil stocked in it. Thanks to its low cost, the PPSh enjoys large popularity among Stalkers, regardless of faction.\n Ammunition:\n 7.62x25mm P \n 7.62x25mm PS </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-ak107">
		<text>AK-107</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak107">
		<text>The AK-107 is a relatively new assault rifle with a recoil-reducing countermass mechanism which is pretty similar to the one used in AEK-971. Its high rate of fire and accuracy make it a decent and efficient rifle. This particular variant is chambered for 5.45 cartridges.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-ak108">
		<text>AK-108</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_ak108">
		<text>The AK-108 is a relatively new assault rifle with a recoil-reducing countermass mechanism which is pretty similar to the one used in AEK-971. Its high rate of fire and accuracy make it a decent and efficient rifle. This particular variant is chambered for 5.56 cartridges.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- V etoy sekcii nahodyatsya skorostrel'nye snayperskie vintovki -->
	<string id="wpn-vintorez">
		<text>VSS Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez">
		<text>Noiseless VSS Vintorez sniper rifle. It is similar in function and construction to the AS Val, to the point where both guns share 70% of their parts. Relatively small recoil combined with specially designed high quality subsonic ammunition with an effective range of 400 meters contribute heavily to its accuracy. The heavy bullet makes almost zero noise due to absence of supersonic shock waves, its weight also helps it stabilize during flight, which has a positive impact on flatness of trajectory.\n Ammunition:\n 9x39mm PAB-9 \n 9x39mm SP-6 </text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-vintorez_m1">
		<text>Modified VSS Vintorez</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-vintorez_m1">
		<text>Custom variant of the noiseless VSS. Clearly someone had put lots of love and effort into this gun. Most of the internal components were made from sturdier materials which in return had a good impact on durability and accuracy. Not to mention the high capacity magazine.\n Ammunition:\n 9x39mm PAB-9 \n 9x39mm SP-6 </text>
	</string>
<!-- V etoy sekcii nahodyatsya snayperskie vintovki -->
	<string id="wpn-svd">
		<text>Dragunov SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svd">
		<text>Dragunov sniper rifle. Almost as reliable as a Kalashnikov, with simplicist design and easy handling. Even a rookie is able to understand the convenient layout of the rifle scope. It proved itself to be an exceptionally efficient and deadly weapon. In the Zone it is preferred mostly by experienced Dutyers.\n Ammunition: \n 7.62x54mmR 7N1 \n 7.62x54mmR 7N13 \n 7.62x54mmR 7N14 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-svd_m1">
		<text>Modified Dragunov SVD</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svd_m1">
		<text>Latest variant of the SVD sniper rifle with polymer furniture and a custom-made magazine. The gunsmith's identity remains a complete mystery. Improved weapon balance resulted in recoil reduction. Comes with a 6x rifle scope.\n Ammunition: \n 7.62x54mmR 7N1 \n 7.62x54mmR 7N13 \n 7.62x54mmR 7N14 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-svu">
		<text>OTs-03A SVU-A</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu">
		<text>SVU-A (Snayperskaya Vintovka Ukorochennaya Avtomaticheskaya). A relatively rare find in the Zone due to limited production. The general idea was to create a shortened version of the SVD sniper rifle with as little negative impact on the accuracy as possible, so the designers went with a bullpup design. The barrel has been shortened and comes with a pre-attached sound suppressor which also acts as a muzzle brake. The plastic pistol grip is located near the middle of the gun and has a comfortable shape. The SVU-A allows for automatic fire, but it should be noted that it should be used only in the most extreme cases of emergency, as both the barrel and the small magazine weren't intended for this kind of abuse.\n Ammunition: \n 7.62x54mmR 7N1 \n 7.62x54mmR 7N13 \n 7.62x54mmR 7N14 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-svu_m1">
		<text>Modified SVU-A</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-svu_m1">
		<text>Slightly modified SVU-A sniper rifle. Most of its parts have been remade from lightweight materials and besides that the gun utilizes a more capacious magazine, a rifle scope with higher magnification and an integrated silencer. As a result, the gun allows for accurate fire at long distances with slightly reduced recoil. The ultimate dream rifle of every sniper. Unfortunately, this rifle has been modified to an extent where cartridge quality has an impact on its operability, making 7N1 rounds no longer suitable for use with this gun.\n Ammunition: \n 7.62x54mmR 7N13 \n 7.62x54mmR 7N14 </text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-gauss">
		<text>Gauss gun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-gauss">
		<text>Project 62 - Incredibly accurate coilgun built on the principles of electromagnetism, developed in secret laboratories hidden deep within the Zone, which are now occupied by the Monolith. It is almost entirely noiseless as the gun utilizes energy of electromagnets instead of gunpowder. Despite the tremendous firepower of the Project 62, the recoil is insignificant. The accuracy of this gun combined with the stopping power and velocity of the cartridge exceed those of all other small arms as the bullet's high kinetic energy renders virtually every bulletproof vest ever useless. A weapon so rare that Stalkers think that the stories about it are bordering on fiction.\n Ammunition: \n 2ı10mm M62 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-sg550sr">
		<text>SIG SG 550 Sniper</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sg550sr">
		<text>SIG SG 550, modified to look and perform like a real sniper rifle.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>	
<!-- V etoy sekcii nahodyatsya pulemety -->
	<string id="ars-rpk74">
		<text>RPK-74M</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_rpk74">
		<text>The RPK-74 is a light machine gun developed during the 1970s in parallel with the AK-74. The main differences are the heavier and longer barrel as well as a humongous stock. The sights have been improved as well. All the aforementioned features had a pretty bad impact on the gun's weight, though additional firepower comes in handy for infantry support and suppression. The modernized variant of RPK-74, the RPK-74M makes an even bigger difference with a side rail for mounting Picatinny rails and scopes. This gun is also fitted with a 75-round drum magazine.\n Ammunition:\n 5.45x39mm 7N6 \n 5.45x39mm 7N22 </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-pkm_name">
		<text>PKM</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-pkm">
		<text>Modernized Kalashnikov general-purpose machine gun. It's big, heavy, belt-fed and very scary, using 100-round munition boxes. Set it up in a right place and you can mow down entire platoons of enemies. Heavy military units assigned for patrolling the Zone are often armed with such machine guns. In the Zone itself it's a pretty rare sight due to its large size and weight. On top of that, using this weapon requires special training and lots of physical preparation.\n %c[255,1,255,255]Ammunition: %c[default] \n%c[255,1,255,255]ï %c[default] 7,62ı54 mm 7N1 - sniper \n%c[255,1,255,255]ï %c[default] 7,62ı54 mm 7N26 - armor-piercing \n%c[255,1,255,255]ï %c[default] 7,62ı54 mm 7N14 - sniper armor-piercing</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-m_134">
		<text>XM214 Microgun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-m_134">
		<text>If any machine gun wasn't enough for a bloodthirsty badass motherfucker like you, here you go, wish granted. Behold, the XM214 - probably the meanest and the most overkill weapon you can find in the Zone. This rotary microgun is a "lightweight" variant of the M134 Minigun, chambered for smaller 5.56 cartridges, resulting in increased rate of fire. It boasts ridiculous firepower and tremendous recoil, although it's heavy as sin. An encapsulated fragment of the "Battery" artefact is used as the gun's energy supply.\n Ammunition: \n 5.56x45mm SS109 \n 5.56x45mm M995 </text>
	</string>
<!-- V etoy sekcii nahodyatsya droboviki -->
	<string id="wpn-bm16">
		<text>Sawn-off TOZ-66</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bm16">
		<text>TOZ-66 hunting shotgun, cut down by a bit. Most people just can't stand how and why would someone want to castrate a gun like that. but sawn-off weaponry still seems to be pretty popular. Much smaller and lighter than the standard hunting shotgun, only effective when used in close combat. Probably the most widespread weapon among rookies, right before the Makarov PM.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-bm16_full">
		<text>TOZ-66</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-bm16_full">
		<text>Full-length TOZ-66 hunting shotgun with horizontal barrel alignment. Most of these have been sawn-off for the rookies, but some of these have been preserved in their original state and thus saved from the castration. The long barrels give this shotgun much-needed accuracy to deal efficiently with the target.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>	
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-toz34">
		<text>TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-toz34">
		<text>Full-length TOZ-34 hunting shotgun, magnificent for dealing with anything made of flesh and bones. Through the utilization of 12 gauge rounds, the damage output is truly devastating. Its only disadvantage is that it's after all a double-barreled hunting shotgun... \n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-toz34_short">
		<text>Sawn-off TOZ-34</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-toz34_short">
		<text>You wanted a hunting shotgun? There's your fucking hunting shotgun. You wanted an actual full-length hunting shotgun with a stock and long barrels? Fuck you. Hunting shotguns require a lot of skill, and that involves aiming. Can you aim? Hell no. Use a sawn-off shotgun, like this one. Its two shortened barrels can do miracles at close range, but the brutal recoil is gonna snap your wrists thrice the moment you pull the trigger.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn_toz34_m1">
		<text>Hunting shotgun</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn_toz34_m1">
		<text>Clearly a custom-made hunting shotgun. The barrels have been rifled, which had a good impact on accuracy and flight trajectory. It also comes with a non-detachable scope.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-sayga12k">
		<text>Saiga-12K</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sayga12k">
		<text>Semi-automatic 12 gauge shotgun built on the basis of the Kalashnikov rifle. The fact it's based off an AK makes it just as simple to use and reliable as one. Horrifyingly efficient in close quarters combat. Its removable magazine makes reloading quicker.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
    <string id="wpn-saiga12c">
		<text>Saiga-12C</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_saiga12c">
		<text>Smoothbore automatic shotgun based off the Saiga-12K. The main differences between this gun and the standard Saiga-12K are the shorter barrel and a folding stock. Despite the changes, it has retained most of the base gun's efficiency and is still able to wreak one hell of a havoc at close range.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
	<!-- // -->
    <string id="wpn-saiga12c_m1">
		<text>"Thresher"</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons1_saiga12c_m1">
		<text>The "Thresher" is a modified automatic Saiga-12C shotgun. Increased rate of fire allows the user to apply more hot lead to anything that moves. Comes with an integrated holographic sight.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>

<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-benelli_short_m1">
		<text>Modified Benelli M3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-benelli_short_m1_s">
		<text>Mod. Benelli M3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-benelli_short_m1">
		<text>Modified variant of the short Benelli M3 shotgun. The main improvements over the standard shortened variant are the more capacious magazine which holds 5 rounds as well as a sturdier barrel.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-spas12">
		<text>Franchi SPAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-spas12">
		<text>Smoothbore automatic shotgun developed during the 70s in Italy, intended for use by the police and military units. Its reliability and automatic fire mode are exceptionally admirable. On the other hand, it's quite heavy and expensive. Nonetheless, you're gonna have a hard time finding a better shotgun than that in the Zone.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-spas12_m1">
		<text>Modified Franchi SPAS-12</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-spas12_m1">
		<text>Slightly modified SPAS-12 shotgun. Its barrel has been rifled as a measure of making the gun more accurate with less spread. However, using buckshot rounds has a bad impact on the gun's reliability.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-wincheaster1300">
		<text>Winchester Model 1300</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-wincheaster1300">
		<text>Smoothbore pump-action shotgun of American origin, designed for use in most demanding scenarios where reliability is of highest importance.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-winchester_m1">
		<text>Modified Winchester 1300</text>
	</string>	
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-winchester_m1">
		<text>"Slightly" modified Winchester 1300, with the one and only change being a small fragment of the "Gravi" artefact shoehorned in the receiver, in a way which increases muzzle velocity.\n Ammunition: \n 12x70mm buckshot \n 12x76 slug \n 12x76 dart </text>
	</string>
	
<!-- // -->
<!-- V dannoy sekcii nahodyatsya granatomety i granaty -->
	<string id="wpn-rpg7">
		<text>RPG-7V</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rpg7">
		<text>The Russian RPG-7V rocket launcher can be considered as one of the most successful weapons in its class. The main purpose of this weapon was to destroy tanks but there's no problem in using it against infantry either. Since there's a big surplus of them in Ukrainian Army warehouses, they must've arrived in the Zone eventually, but so far Stalkers have never seen or held one yet. Its bulky dimensions and weight aren't something to sing odes about, but when you want to take out multiple times at once from a large distance, it's certainly irreplaceable.\n Ammunition:\n TBG-7V warheads </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="mil_m202_name">
		<text>M202 FLASH</text>
	</string>
	<string id="mil_m202_desc">
		<text>The M202 is an American multishot rocket launcher, featuring four tubes that can load 66 mm incendiary rockets. It has two fire modes: Single fire mode where only one rocket is fired from one barrel and a mode where all four rockets are fired at once. The M74 rockets are equipped with M235 warheads containing incendiary material with blast radius of 20 meters. Nowadays pretty much deprecated by newer and more efficient rocket launchers. As a side effect of its "retirement", it started to "disappear" from military warehouses, only to appear back in various exotic places. The main problem with the M202 was the ammunition which was ridden with manufacturing flaws, resulting in self-ignition of warheads during loading of the weapon.\n Ammunition:\n M74 rockets </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-rg-6">
		<text>RG6 6G30</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rg-6">
		<text>A bulky and heavy revolver-type grenade launcher with a folding stock. Its mechanism isn't very different from the one used in the GP-25. Despite its size and weight, it's a very useful toy, particularly when targeting large numbers of mutants, attacking well-guarded stationary objects or fighting tough creatures. \n Ammunition:\n VOG-25 grenade \n VOG-25P grenade </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-rg6_m1">
		<text>RG6 6G30 M406</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-rg6_m1">
		<text>Standard RG6 grenade launcher, slightly modified to utilize 40mm grenades used by western militaries.\n Ammunition: \n 40mm M406</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="grenade-f1">
		<text>F1 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-f1">
		<text>Common anti-personnel frag grenade, coloquially referred to as "limonka". Still used by the Russian Army since the Great Patriotic War. Those who haven't been hit by the explosion itself are going suffer from shrapnel-induced damage. Toss only from from behind cover.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="st_grenade_gd5">
		<text>GD-5 smoke grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-gd05">
		<text>A standard smoke grenade. Once it's deployed and thrown, it hisses out a smoke screen which masks your movements for about ten seconds.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="st_grenade_light">
		<text>OG-1 illumination grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="st_grenade_lights">
		<text>OG-1</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade_light">
		<text>Chemical OG-1 illumination grenade, used mostly during night operations to shed a light on its surroundings, disorienting the enemy in meanwhile. It takes a couple of minutes before the chemical burns out.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="grenade-rgd5">
		<text>RGD-5 grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade-rgd5">
		<text>An offensive hand grenade with a small radius of splinter damage.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="grenade_gas">
		<text>HG-3 gas grenade</text>
	</string>
	<string id="grenade_gas_s">
		<text>HG-3</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_grenade_gas">
		<text>Chemical grenade containing a toxic nerve agent which tears the victim's lungs apart from inside while burning out their skin. Smells like Yperite. Once deployed, the gas remains active for a few minutes.</text>
	</string>
<!-- V dannoy sekcii nahodyatsya glushiteli -->
	<string id="ars-sil_1143_p">
		<text>M11.43-P silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_1143_p">
		<text>A silencer made for weapons chambered for 11.43x23mm (.45 ACP) ammunition.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-sil_545_ar">
		<text>M5.45-¿ silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_545_ar">
		<text>A silencer made for the custom Groza rifle chambered for 5.45x39mm ammunition.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-sil_556_ar">
		<text>Ã5.56-¿ silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_556_ar">
		<text>A silencer made for weapons chambered for 5.56x45mm ammunition.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-sil_762_ar">
		<text>M7.62-¿ silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_ar">
		<text>A silencer made for weapons chambered for 7.62x39mm ammunition.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="ars-sil_762_pms">
		<text>M7.62-PMS silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_arsenal_sil_762_pms">
		<text>A silencer made for weapons chambered for 7.62x54mm ammunition</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-addon-silencer">
		<text>PBS silencer</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-addon-silencer">
		<text>A silencer made by Zone gunsmiths. Its construction is remniscent of the PBS-4 silencer for the AKS-74U carbine. Reducing the gunfire's sound signature sounds useful, but has a bad impact on reliability. There's no point in using a silencer for automatic fire - there's very little sound signature reduction and the silencer is very prone to failure.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-9mm_nato-silencer">
		<text>9mm silencer (NATO)</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-9mm_nato-silencer">
		<text>A silencer made for weapons chambered for 9x19mm ammunition.</text>
	</string>
<!-- V dannoy sekcii nahodyatsya pricely -->
	<string id="addon_scope_acog">
		<text>ACOG scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_acog">
		<text>A 4x magnification ACOG scope produced for the American military. It can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_zf4">
		<text>ZF4 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_zf4">
		<text>Carl Zeiss Jena ZF4 optical sight with 4x magnification. Made in Nazi Germany. Comes with a scope mount compatible with the MP 40.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope">
		<text>PSO-1 scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope">
		<text>A widely used Soviet scope with 4x magnification. The scope can be mounted using a dovetail mount used by any Warsaw Pact weapon.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope_susat">
		<text>SUSAT scope</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope_susat">
		<text>A 4x magnification SUSAT scope produced for the British military, mostly seen on rifles like the SA80. It can be attached to any weapon with a Picatinny rail.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="addon_scope2">
		<text>DOCTER sight</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_addon_scope2">
		<text>DOCTER red dot sight. Its robust design and use of high quality materials make it a very durable product. Its nitrogen filling prevents fogging during sudden changes of temperature.</text>
	</string>
<!-- V dannoy sekcii nahodyatsya vse ostal'nye predmety -->
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-knife">
		<text>Sharpened bayonet</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn-flame">
	    <text>Flamethrower</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_wpn-flame">
		<text>A makeshift flamethrower constructed by a freedomer called Screw. Its main and obvious purpose is to set things on fire, mostly organic lifeforms. The flamethrower's design is fairly simple - it projects a stream of flammable liquid which is then ignited spontaneously in air. Due to the high reactivity of the flammable mixture, some parts of the flamethrower have been made from high-quality corrosion-resistant materials produced in special laboratory conditions. How did Screw manage to gain access to such materials is known by no one else but him. Due to rarity of high-quality materials in the Zone, Screw's flamethrower was unable to be mass-produced, which is a big shame.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->	
	<string id="wpn-arb">
		<text>Crossbow</text>
	</string>
    <string id="enc_weapons_wpn-arb">
		<text>A hunting crossbow with a built-in optical sight. It's an almost noiseless weapon with great efficiency in hands of a skilled sniper, even despite its very limited rate of fire. Crossbows are mostly used by foreign mutant hunters - of course only a foreigner would be stupid enough to bring a single-shot weapon to a hunt, which often makes them end up dead.\n Ammunition:\n Crossbow bolt </text>
    </string>	
<!-- // -->
	<string id="montirovka">
		<text>Freeman's crowbar</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_montirovka">
		<text>Simple heavy crowbar which used to belong to a foreigner called Freeman. The handle has an inscription engraved on it - "Manufactured for Black Mesa"</text>
	</string>
	
	<string id="montirovka_weak">
		<text>Lead pipe</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_montirovka_weak">
		<text>Probably the most common thing you'd expect to find in the Zone. If you use it properly, you might even be able to bash someone's skull in.</text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->
	<string id="wpn_glock">
		<text>Glock 17</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_glock-desc">
		<text>One of the most widespread pistols in Europe, especially among police forces. Developed in Austria by Glock GmbH for the Austrian Army. As one of the first pistols developed by this company, it turned out to be a quite comfortable, lightweight and reliable weapon. Currently serves as the main service pistol of the Austrian Army under the designation P80.\n Ammunition:\n 9x19mm FMJ \n 9x19mm DD </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->	
	<string id="wpn-aps">
		<text>Stechkin APS</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn-aps_desc">
		<text>The Stechkin automatic pistol (APS) was developed somewhen in between the 40s and 50s by Igor Yakovlevich Stechkin and was adopted by the Soviet Army in 1951. The pistol was intented to be a personal defense weapon for soldiers and officers who didn't need to rely on the Kalashnikov rifle or the SKS and regarded the Makarov pistol as garbage. In comparison with the Makarov, the APS curb-stomps it in almost every aspect - superior firepower, high rate of fire, bigger magazine and a longer barrel.\n Ammunition:\n 9x18mm PM \n 9x18mm PBM \n 9x18mm PMM </text>
	</string>
<!-- // -->	
	<string id="st_knife_m1">
		<text>Serega Maniac's knife</text>
	</string>
	<string id="knife_m1_desc">
		<text>A well-made hunting knife with a serrated blade. The handle has a name inscribed on it: Serega Maniac.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="wpn-arb_spec">
		<text>Doctor's crossbow</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons_wpn-arb_spec">
		<text>This custom crossbow is a vastly powerful weapon, with some of its components remade to launch the bolt in higher speeds. The only drawback is that only taser bolts are compatible with it.</text>
	</string>
	<string id="ammo-arbolt_spec">
		<text>Taser bolt</text>
	</string>
	<string id="enc_weapons1_ammo_ammo-arbolt_spec">
		<text>Custom-made crossbow bolt with a taser module. Made to be used specifically with Doctor's crossbow.</text>
	</string>

	<string id="wpn_pkm_digger_name">
		<text>PKM "Digger Yura"</text>
	</string>
	<string id="wpn_pkm_digger">
		<text>This machine gun was named after its previous owner. The main differences are a bigger ammo box and increased rate of fire.</text>
	</string>
</string_table>
